<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>This book makes appear the claim, pedigree and proceedings of James Percy now claimant to the Earldom of Northumberland humbly presented to both Houses of Parliament.</title>
            <author>Percy, James, 1619-1690?</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 164 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 30 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A54308</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P1460</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R30769</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11467358</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11467358</idno>
            <idno type="VID">47799</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A54308)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 47799)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1467:22)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>This book makes appear the claim, pedigree and proceedings of James Percy now claimant to the Earldom of Northumberland humbly presented to both Houses of Parliament.</title>
                  <author>Percy, James, 1619-1690?</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[58] p. in various pagings.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint date illegible on t.p. Date provided by NUC pre-1956 imprint.</note>
                  <note>Includes: "A narrative of the proceedings of the petitioner," and various petitions to the King and Houses of Parliament.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign Campus). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Writ of error --  Great Britain.</term>
               <term>Nobility --  Great Britain.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:47799:1"/>
            <p>THIS BOOK Makes appear the <hi>Claim, Pedigree, and Proceedings</hi> OF JAMES PERCY Now CLAIMANT to the EARLDOM OF Northumberland, Humbly preſented to both Houſes of <hi>Parliament.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Printed in the Year 16<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="preface">
            <pb facs="tcp:47799:2"/>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>His Preface is only to tell the Readers that all new matters are ſtill placed in the Front of this Book, which ſeems Irregular; but read this with Patience, and in time it may be Regulated, and put into a due Form.</p>
            <p>In ſhort I cannot nor muſt not forget Truth and Juſtice, nor the Actions of juſt Men.</p>
            <p>For Sir <hi>Thomas Percy</hi> K<hi rend="sup">nt.</hi> was courted to take upon him the Title and Earldom of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> but he refus'd it. becauſe he knew himſelf to be Deſcended from Sir <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Percy</hi> K<hi rend="sup">nt.</hi> 
               <hi>Lord</hi> Egermond, <hi>2d.</hi> Brother to <hi>Henry Percy</hi> 3d. Earl of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Captain <hi>Percy</hi> of <hi>Beverly</hi> did look after the Earldom of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and to preſerve the name of <hi>Percy,</hi> but he left off his Claim, by reaſon he ſound himſelf to be Deſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cended from one of the Brothers of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> 5th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Now Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy</hi> K<hi rend="sup">nt.</hi> was the <hi>3d.</hi> Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> 5th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> who had <hi>2</hi> Sons, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>1. Henry</hi> had Iſſue <hi>3.</hi> Sons,
<list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>James,</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>William,</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Henry.</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>
                              <hi>James</hi> Claimant.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>2. Robert,</hi> had Iſsue; <hi>3</hi> Sons,
<list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Robert,</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Thomas,</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>&amp; one more
<list>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Alexander, Roger, Francis,</hi>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>depiction of half-moon</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>God hath not ſet the <hi>Half-moon</hi> in vain upon the Claimant, but the World may look upon it to be the Almigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties Candle to find out the true Heir-Male, <hi>James Percy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now for <hi>Alexander Percy</hi> Gent. of <hi>Ireland,</hi> that rides in the Life-guard, and Mr. <hi>Roger Percy</hi> Shoe-maker at <hi>Charing-croſs;</hi> and Mr. <hi>Francis Percy</hi> Stone-cutter in <hi>Cambridge,</hi> and his Brother a <hi>Taylor:</hi> I acknowledg them to be Couſins, and Deſcended from the Sons of <hi>Robert Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy,</hi> my Great <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nkle.</p>
            <p>And by reaſon I know not which is the Eldeſt and neareſt of Kin of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Collateral Line.</p>
            <p>Therefor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> moſt humbly pray, <hi>That the</hi> Heralds <hi>may take notice, and help them to find out the truth of</hi> Seniority.</p>
            <p>For my Cordial Endeavours are, to preſerve the <hi>Moon</hi> from being Miſted or Eclipſed any more.</p>
            <list>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:2"/>
               <item>HENRY PERCY, 5th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Married; and had Iſſue 3 Sons, <hi>viz.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>I. <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> 6th. Earl of <hi>Northumber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> Married, and dyed without Iſſue.</item>
                     <item>II. <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> Married, and had Iſſue; But when <hi>Joſceline Percy</hi> the 11th. Earl dyed; the Heirs Males of this Line were Extinct alſo.</item>
                     <item>III. Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy,</hi> Married and had Iſſue 2 Sons, <hi>(viz.) Henry,</hi> and <hi>Robert.</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Eldeſt Son, Married, and had Iſſue 3 Sons <hi>(viz.) James, William,</hi> and <hi>Henry;</hi> But the 2 elder Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers dyed without Iſſue-male
<list>
                                 <item>
                                    <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> (Third Son,) Married, and had Iſſue 3 Sons <hi>(viz.) Henry, James,</hi> and <hi>Henry:</hi> But the two <hi>Henries</hi> dyed young.
<list>
                                       <item>
                                          <hi>James Percy,</hi> (the now Claimant) Married, and hath 3 Sons, <hi>(viz.) Anthony, Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry,</hi> and <hi>John.</hi>
                                          <list>
                                             <item>
                                                <hi>Anthony Percy,</hi> is Married, and hath Iſſue, <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Grandſon of <hi>James Percy</hi> the now Claimant.</item>
                                          </list>
                                       </item>
                                    </list>
                                 </item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>Percy coat of arms with half-moon</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>The following Account makes out this</hi> Pedigree <hi>fully, and at large down from</hi> Henry Percy 5th. <hi>Earl of</hi> Northumberland, <hi>to the Claim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ant</hi> James Percy, <hi>his</hi> Sons, <hi>and</hi> Grand-ſon, Henry Percy.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:47799:3"/>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:47799:3"/>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="pedigree">
                        <head>A True Pedegree to prove the Claymant, <hi>James Percy,</hi> to be the ſecond Son of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> of <hi>Horton</hi> in the County of <hi>Northampton,</hi> who was third Son of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> of <hi>Parvenham</hi> in the County of <hi>Bedford,</hi> who was the eldeſt Son of Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy,</hi> K<hi rend="sup">nt.</hi> who was the third Son of <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, 5<hi rend="sup">th.</hi>
                           </hi> Earl of <hi>Northum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland,</hi> By which Deſcent the Claymant is Couſin and next Heir-male to <hi>Joſcelin Percy</hi> the late and <hi>11<hi rend="sup">th.</hi>
                           </hi> Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Deceaſed.</head>
                        <figure>
                           <figDesc>Percy coat of arms</figDesc>
                        </figure>
                        <p>
                           <hi>
                              <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>ENRY</hi> Lord <hi>PERCY,</hi> Fifth Earl of <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland,</hi> Lord of the Honours of <hi>Cocker<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mouth</hi> and <hi>Petworth,</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Lucy, Poy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nings, Fitz-payne</hi> and <hi>Bryan,</hi> and Knight of the moſt Noble Order of the Garter,</p>
                        <p>Who married <hi>Katherine,</hi> one of the Daughters and Co-heirs of Sir <hi>Robert Spencer</hi> Knight; by whom he had Iſſue.</p>
                        <p>1ſt. <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy,</hi> 6th. Earl of <hi>Northumber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> who Dyed without Iſſue.</p>
                        <p>2d. <hi>Thomas Percy</hi> Knight, who was Executed; had to Wife, <hi>Eleanor,</hi> one of the Daughters and Co-heirs of Sir <hi>Gwichard Harbottle</hi> Knight; by whom he had Iſſue, <hi>Thomas</hi> the 7th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> who was beheaded at <hi>York,</hi> and dyed without Iſſue-male; And <hi>Henry</hi> the 8th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> whoſe Iſſue is incerted hereafter.</p>
                        <p>3d. Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy</hi> Knight, who was married, as by the Oath of Mr. <hi>Henry Champion,</hi> who kept the Books and Records of the <hi>Percies.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy</hi> 6th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Lord of the Honours of <hi>Cockermouth</hi> and <hi>Petworth,</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Lucy, Poynings, Fitz-payne</hi> and <hi>Bryan,</hi> Knight of the moſt Noble Order of the Garter, who Dyed at <hi>Hackny</hi> near <hi>London</hi> the day before the Calends of <hi>July</hi> 1537. leaving no Children behind him, The Dignity of the Earl of <hi>Northum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland</hi> was vacant till the time of <hi>Edward</hi> VI. <hi>John Dudly</hi> Earl of <hi>Warwick,</hi> Viſcount <hi>Liſie,</hi> Lord <hi>Baſſet</hi> and <hi>Tyes</hi> was intituled Duke of <hi>Northumberland</hi> the 5th. year of King <hi>Edward</hi> VI. But when he was Dead, <hi>Thomas Percy</hi> Nephew to this <hi>Henry</hi> by <hi>Thomas</hi> his Brother, who was Executed; In the Reign of Qu. <hi>Mary,</hi> was reſtor'd to all the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours of that Family.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> Nephew to <hi>Henry</hi> 6th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland</hi> by his Brother <hi>Thomas,</hi> when the ſtock of the <hi>Percies</hi> were fading; to their Relief was inveſted to the Earldom of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> which the Earl of <hi>Warwick</hi> held before; and thereby was the 7th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland</hi> of that Family, Lord of the Honours of <hi>Cockermouth, Petworth,</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Lucy, Poynings, Fitz-payne</hi> and <hi>Bryan;</hi> Queen <hi>Mary</hi> beſtowing thoſe Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours upon him, and his Heirs Male; (and for want of ſuch Iſſue, Then to <hi>Henry</hi> his Brother, and his Heirs Male,) by her Letters Patents, dated the <hi>first</hi> day of <hi>May</hi> 1557: and whatſoever elſe of the Antient Patrimonies of the Earls remained, Seiſed, or For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited: But if He ſhould die without Iſſue Male, Then it ſhould go to his Brother <hi>Henry,</hi> and his Iſſue Male. And although (to Honour him the more,) Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi> made him Knight of the moſt Noble Order of the Garter; Yet He, (unmindful of all theſe Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefits,)
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:47799:4"/>Conſpir'd with <hi>Charles</hi> Earl of <hi>Weſtmerland,</hi> to Depoſe, by Force, Qu. <hi>Elizabeth;</hi> So by Authority of Parliament he was Condemned for High Treaſon, and as Chief in the Conſpiracy, was beheaded at <hi>York,</hi> 14th. year of Queen <hi>Elizabeth.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Who married <hi>Anne</hi> the Daughter of <hi>Henry Somerſet</hi> Earl of <hi>Worceſter,</hi> and had Iſſue Male, <hi>Thomas,</hi> that dyed young, and 4 Daughters; Heirs Males Extinct, And</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry Percy</hi> 8th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Lord of the Honours of <hi>Cockermouth, Pet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth,</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Lucy, Poynings, Fitz-payne</hi> and <hi>Bryan;</hi> all which Honours he en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joy'd by virtue of the Letters Patents given by Queen <hi>Mary</hi> to his Brother <hi>Thomas,</hi> and was Created <hi>Anno</hi> 1574. He was after accuſed of Treaſon; and being in the Tower of <hi>London,</hi> ſlew himſelf with a Dag charg'd with Two Bullets, (before his Cauſe was heard, or that he was Arraigned,) in the Month of <hi>July</hi> 1585.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>ARMS Quarter'd as before,</hi> Who married <hi>Katherine</hi> one of the Daughters and Co-heirs of <hi>John Nevel</hi> Lord <hi>Latimer,</hi> by whom he had Iſſue,
<list>
                              <item>1. <hi>Henry</hi> the 9th. Earl.</item>
                              <item>2. <hi>Thomas,</hi> who dyed young.</item>
                              <item>3. <hi>William.</hi>
                              </item>
                              <item>4. Sir <hi>Charles Percy</hi> Knight.</item>
                              <item>5. Sir <hi>Richard Percy</hi> Knight.</item>
                              <item>6. Sir <hi>Alan Percy</hi> Knight.</item>
                              <item>7. Sir <hi>Joſceline Percy</hi> Knight.</item>
                              <item>8. <hi>George Percy</hi> 
                                 <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
                              </item>
                           </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy</hi> 9th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Lord of the Honours of <hi>Cockermouth,</hi> and <hi>Petworth,</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Lucy, Poynings, Fitz-payne,</hi> and <hi>Bryan,</hi> and (in his Mothers right,) Lord <hi>Latimer;</hi> He was Knight of the moſt Noble Order of the Garter, by Qu. <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> in the Year of our Lord 1593.</p>
                        <p>Who marryed <hi>Dorothy,</hi> Daughter of <hi>Walter Devereux,</hi> Earl of <hi>Eſſex;</hi> by whom he had Iſſue,
<list>
                              <item>1. <hi>Algernon,</hi> the 10th. Earl.</item>
                              <item>2. Lord <hi>Henry,</hi> who dyed without Iſſue.</item>
                           </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Algernon,</hi> the 10th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Lord of the Honours of <hi>Cockermouth</hi> and <hi>Petworth,</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Lucy, Poynings, Fitz-payne, Bryan</hi> and <hi>Latimer,</hi> Knight of the moſt Noble Order of the Garter, <hi>Lord Admiral</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> and <hi>General</hi> over His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Forces for his Expedition 1640. and one of His Majeſties moſt Honourable Privy Council: He marryed Two Wives: by the former he had 4 Daughters; and by the latter Wife, 1 Son, <hi>(viz.) Joſceline.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Joſceline,</hi> the 11th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Lord of the Honours of <hi>Cockermouth</hi> and <hi>Petworth,</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Lucy, Poynings, Fitz-payne, Bryan</hi> and <hi>Latimer,</hi> Deceaſed;</p>
                        <p>Who married <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> Daughter to the Earl of <hi>Southampton,</hi> by whom he had Iſſue
<list>
                              <item>1. <hi>Henry,</hi> who dyed young.</item>
                              <item>2. <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> who marry'd the Lord <hi>Ogle. (Heirs Males Extinct.)</hi>
                              </item>
                           </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>The Collateral Line.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy,</hi> the 3d. and youngeſt Son of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> the 5th. Earl of <hi>Northum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland;</hi> who married, and had Sons and Daughters, as by the Oath of Mr. <hi>Henry Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pion,</hi> who kept the <hi>Percies</hi> Books and Records; where he found what he teſtify'd upon Oath, at the Tryal between <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>tting</hi> Plaintiff, and <hi>Coppleſton</hi> Defendant; He had Iſſue,
<list>
                              <item>1. <hi>Henry Percy,</hi>
                              </item>
                              <item>2. <hi>Robert Percy,</hi>
                              </item>
                           </list> and 2 Daughters.</p>
                        <p>About 1559. theſe 4 Children were (in the time of Troubles in Queen <hi>Elizabeths</hi> Days) ſent out of the North in Hampers, to old Dame <hi>Vaux</hi> at <hi>Haraden</hi> in <hi>Northamp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tonſhire,</hi> and there were brought up, preſerved, and provided for. Therefore it is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded by all, that Sir <hi>Ingelram</hi>'s Lady, (the Mother of thoſe Children, (muſt be related to Dame <hi>Vaux</hi>'s Family.</p>
                        <p>The Counteſs <hi>Dowager</hi> of <hi>Dorſet, Pembrook,</hi> and <hi>Mountgomery,</hi> ſaid, <hi>That if the Clai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mant,</hi> James Percy, <hi>were her Kinſman, he muſt be deſcended of thoſe Children that were ſent into the</hi> South <hi>in Hampers.</hi> [Note] There were but few Coaches in thoſe days. <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garet</hi> that married the firſt Earl of <hi>Cumberland,</hi> whom the Counteſs of <hi>Dorſet</hi> deſcended from, was Sir <hi>Ingelram Percie's</hi> own Siſter. And while the Claymant was with this Lady, enquiring and delivering Declarations in Ejectment, the Eſtate was all-begg'd, as his printed Book makes appear more at large.</p>
                        <p>That which wildernized the Claymant, was, the rending the matchings of the <hi>Percies</hi> out of the Herald's Book, and likewiſe the Herald-painter left Sir <hi>Ingelram</hi> quite out of the firſt Pedegree.</p>
                        <p>
                           <pb n="7" facs="tcp:47799:4"/>
                           <hi>Henry,</hi> the eldeſt Son of Sir <hi>Ingelram</hi> marryed the Daughter of one <hi>Tibott,</hi> by whom he had Iſſue,
<list>
                              <item>1. <hi>James Percy,</hi> who dyed about the year 1654. in <hi>Ireland,</hi> without Iſſue-male.</item>
                              <item>2. <hi>William,</hi> who died young.</item>
                              <item>3. <hi>Henry.</hi>
                              </item>
                           </list> And 3 Daughters.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry Percy</hi> married <hi>Lidea</hi> the Daughter of Mr. <hi>Robert Cope</hi> of <hi>Horton</hi> in <hi>Northamp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tonſhire,</hi> by whom he had Iſſue,
<list>
                              <item>1. <hi>Henry,</hi> who dyed young.</item>
                              <item>2. <hi>James.</hi>
                              </item>
                              <item>3. <hi>Henry,</hi> who dyed young.</item>
                           </list> 1 Daughter, named <hi>Elizabeth.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>James,</hi> the now Claymant, born 1619. of <hi>Henry</hi> and <hi>Lidea</hi> his Wife, who was 2d. Son of <hi>Henry,</hi> who was firſt Son of Sir <hi>Ingelram,</hi> who was 3d. Son of <hi>Henry,</hi> 5th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> who was great great Grandfather of the Claymant <hi>James Percy,</hi> who married <hi>Sarah</hi> the Daughter of <hi>John Sayer</hi> of <hi>Norwich,</hi> Gent. by whom he hath Iſſue,
<list>
                              <item>1. <hi>Anthony Percy,</hi> married and hath a Son <hi>(viz.) Henry.</hi>
                              </item>
                              <item>2. <hi>Henry.</hi>
                              </item>
                              <item>3. <hi>John.</hi>
                              </item>
                           </list>
                        </p>
                        <figure>
                           <figDesc>depiction of half-moon</figDesc>
                        </figure>
                        <p>UPon a tripartine Exchange, the Countries from <hi>Trent,</hi>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>Sir W. Chur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chil's Hiſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry; fel.</hi> 257.</note> to the North-ward, was the Lot of the <hi>Percies,</hi> in Memory whereof the ſame being in the <hi>Georgraphical</hi> Form of an Malf-moon, Creſcent for their Cognizance</p>
                        <p>A ſhort Abſtract of the fore-going Narrative, co-temporizing down from <hi>Henry</hi> the 5th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> who had as before the following (Iſſue) 6th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland, Henry</hi> eldeſt Son, who dyed without Iſſue.</p>
                        <list>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Thomas</hi> ſecond Son had two Sons, both Earls.
<list>
                                 <item>7th. and 8th. Earls, <hi>Thomas,</hi> and <hi>Henry,</hi> firſt Couſins unto —
<list>
                                       <item>9th. Earl, <hi>Henry,</hi> and his Bretheren, ſecond Couſins unto—
<list>
                                             <item>10th. Earl, <hi>Algernon</hi> and his Brother, third Couſins unto—
<list>
                                                   <item>11th. Earl, <hi>Joſcelin,</hi> fourth Couſin unto—
<list>
                                                         <item>The Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy</hi> married to the Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> 5th. Couſin unto —</item>
                                                      </list>
                                                   </item>
                                                </list>
                                             </item>
                                          </list>
                                       </item>
                                    </list>
                                 </item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                           <item>Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy</hi> third Son had two Sons, <hi>viz.</hi>
                              <list>
                                 <item>
                                    <hi>Henry,</hi>
                                    <list>
                                       <item>
                                          <hi>James,</hi>
                                       </item>
                                       <item>
                                          <hi>Henry.</hi>
                                          <list>
                                             <item>
                                                <hi>James.</hi>
                                                <list>
                                                   <item>
                                                      <hi>Anthony,</hi>
                                                      <list>
                                                         <item>—<hi>Henry.</hi>
                                                         </item>
                                                      </list>
                                                   </item>
                                                   <item>
                                                      <hi>Henry,</hi>
                                                   </item>
                                                   <item>
                                                      <hi>John.</hi>
                                                   </item>
                                                </list>
                                             </item>
                                          </list>
                                       </item>
                                       <item>
                                          <hi>Robert.</hi>
                                       </item>
                                    </list>
                                 </item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                        <p>This may ſatisfie all wiſe Men of the Truth of this Pedigree; As for the Claymant <hi>James Percy,</hi> he doth acknowledge the miſtake of claiming under Sir <hi>Richard Percy,</hi> who was born <hi>Anno</hi> 1573. And <hi>James Percy,</hi> who was Unckle and Godfather to the Claymant, was born 1581. So by this Account Sir <hi>Richard</hi> muſt have been a Grandfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther at 8 years of Age. This is an impoſſible thing indeed.</p>
                        <p>But here lies the Myſtery, and the very Truth of this matter; and it was his Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cels advice, to fix upon a wrong party, which (ſaid they) would be the only way to find out the right party; For the Matches of the <hi>Percies</hi> was rent out of the Heralds book, and Sir <hi>Ingelram Percie</hi>'s Name was quite left out of the firſt Pedegree, which wilder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nized the Claymant, and the Councels too, which forced the Claymants Councel to tell the Lords in Parliamant, that the Cauſe did not lie before their Lordſhips, but ought to be tryed before the inferiour Courts firſt; and if the Law could not end it, then it was to return, and come before their Lordſhips again, to debate and to determine: Since which time it hath been found out by a Verdict at Law, that <hi>James Percy,</hi> is the Legitimate Son of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> and <hi>Lidia</hi> his Wife. And upon Petitions, as in the printed Book may appear, The Kings Moſt Excellent Majeſty hath graciouſly conde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcended that the Lords in Parliament ſhall determine the ſaid Cauſe.</p>
                        <p>
                           <pb n="8" facs="tcp:47799:5"/>It is hoped that this juſt account will abate that miſtake of Clayming under Sir <hi>Richard;</hi> for the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hayls</hi> ſaid at the firſt Tryal, <hi>That the Plaintiff had proved himſelf Legitimate by Father and Mother, by Grandfather and Grandmother, but had taken his Deſcent too Low, he must go a ſtep or two Higher.</hi> And the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Rainſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford</hi> ſaid to the Jury at that Tryal againſt <hi>Wright</hi> for Scandal, <hi>That the Plaintiff had pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved himſelf Legitimate,</hi> and therefore did not examine the third part of his Witneſſes; but ſaid <hi>His Pedegree was fully proved at a Tryal before that Court.</hi> So that the Plaintiff ought to have had a Verdict then, when Mr. <hi>Henry Champion</hi>'s Oath did perfect and fix'd the Pedegree as before-declared. And the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Scroggs,</hi> at the laſt Tryal a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt <hi>Blaickstone</hi> for Scandal, and the whole Court did own the Pedegree of the Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff, only ſaid, <hi>The Declaration was nought.</hi> When in Truth it was debated and allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed at the firſt part of the Tryal; which is good Cauſe of Error. As the Claymant hath laboured to find out the Truth, even ſo he doth moſt humbly pray, That all Wiſe, Lear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, and Conſcientious men may take Courage, like the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hayls</hi> and his Brethren, and ſtrictly inquire into the very bottom of the matter, and to ſet aſide all miſtakes, and ſet up Truth, and maintain and ſpeak cordially to and for Juſtice; this being the only way to clear the Innocent and put a ſtop to Oppreſſion. And the Relieved (as in Duty bound) ſhall ever pray for his Majeſties long Life, and the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſperity of Him, His Realms, and Kingdoms.</p>
                        <p>The above Claymant had two Petitions read in Council, 21 <hi>July</hi> 1680. (and rejected) It ſeems it was objected, that the Man whom the Claymant claimed under muſt be a Grandfather at eight years old. It is hoped the account aforeſaid will juſtly ſatisfie and procure a right underſtanding at the ſecond hearing before the Lords in Parliament And there being no preſident, as the Claymant is informed, that the Orders of this Houſe do perpetually bar, where the party hath not been fully heard.</p>
                        <list>
                           <item>For <hi>Henry,</hi> 5th. Earl, had Sir <hi>Ingelram,</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>— who had <hi>Henry,</hi> and he had <hi>Henry,</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>— who had <hi>James</hi> the Claymant.</item>
                        </list>
                        <p>This Truth is as clear as the Sun at Noon-day, and blows over the miſty miſtake of Claiming nnder Sir <hi>Richard Percy.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>It was the putting down of the Court of Wards, and ſetting up of Priviledges on all ſides againſt the true Heir-male, and the general neglect of the Heralds in the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lateral Line, and the treacherous Actings of his Solicitor, did obſtruct and delay all this time.</p>
                        <p>Moreover, the Lord <hi>Ogle</hi> that married the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> hath endeavoured to change his Name from <hi>Cavendiſh</hi> to <hi>Percy,</hi> and alſo to have obtained an Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament to ſettle and confirm upon him (the aforeſaid Lord <hi>Ogle</hi>) all thoſe Lands which are annexed to the Title and Earldom of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> which Lands formerly were firmly ſettled upon the Heir-males of the <hi>Percies</hi> for ever.— See the Records and the Verdict exemplified, and pray a ſtop may be put to the Lord <hi>Ogle's</hi> Act of Parliament, by reaſon the Lands are begg'd, bought, ſold and ſcattered. The undoubted Right, and next Heir-male of the <hi>Percies</hi> in Bloud, and ſo proved at Law, and therefore he moſt humbly and earneſtly prays, <hi>That an Act of Parliament may be had, to restore him to his</hi> Birth-right, Title, Eſtate, Preheminence, Priviledges, Place <hi>and</hi> Seat <hi>of his An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cestors, As it hath been done heretofore to ſeveral of the</hi> Percies, <hi>the Earl of</hi> Kent <hi>and others.</hi> This being the 11th. Year of the Claim of</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>JAMES PERCY. Who humbly Beggs, Prays, and Cries for ſpeedy Juſtice.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:5"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the Kings Moſt Excellent Majeſty.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>JAMES PERCY,</hi> Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Grand-Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Great Grand-ſon of Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> Great great Grand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> Fifth Earl, and Couzen, and next Heir-Male to <hi>Jocelin Percy,</hi> the late and Eleventh Earl of <hi>NORTHUMBERLAND,</hi> Deceaſed.</head>
                        <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                        <p>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hat Your Petitioner hath near upon Ten Years proſecuted his Birth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right, and ſtill continues his Claim to the Title, Honours, Manors, Lands, Preheminencies and Priviledges, that the Rights belonging to the Heirs-male of the <hi>Percies</hi> Family, as they are annexed to the Earldom of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That upon the firſt Addreſs Your Petitioner humbly made to your Majeſty, in order to obtain his Right, Your Majeſty was Graciouſly pleaſed to return for Anſwer, <hi>God forbid Your Majesty ſhould hinder an Heir, but that He ſhould have the Benefit of the Law.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That upon his Application to the Houſe of Lords (after ſome ſhort pleadings,) his Councel moved, thar the Cauſe might be left to the Law for his Legitimation, that he might more Regularly come before their Lordſhips, which was accordingly done.</p>
                        <p>That he hath (purſuant to their Lordſhips order) obtained a Verdict, exemplified under the Seal of your Majeſties Court of <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> That He is truly, and legi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timately deſcended of the Blood and Family of the <hi>Percies</hi> of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That upon Your Petitioners Humble Application by way of Petition to Your Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meſty, praying your Royal Writ of Summons, to call Your Petitioner to Sit in the Houſe of Lords; Your Majeſties Gracious Anſwer was, <hi>That You thought it not Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient until the Petitioners Cauſe was Determined by the Lords.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That the Parliament being by your Majeſties Royal Prerogative again Prorogued, it much encourageth your Petitioners Opponents, and weakens your Petitioner in his Dependencies, having been Publiſhed in the <hi>Gazet</hi> formerly for an Impoſtor, whereupon, by the (contrivance of his Solicitor) the Lands were begg'd in the Name of the Duke of <hi>Monmouth,</hi> and others.</p>
                        <p>That during the time Your Petitioner was proſecuting his Right at Law, the po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent Defendants put him off ſo long by Priviledge of Parliament, till <hi>George Fitz-Roy</hi> was Created Earl of <hi>Northumberland:</hi> And now it is divulged in Print, that the <hi>Lord Ogle,</hi> hath changed his Name from <hi>Cavendiſh</hi> to <hi>Percy:</hi> All which forces your Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioner to flie to Your Sacred Majeſty for Relief, Protection and Juſtice.</p>
                        <p>That it is the Opinion of your Petitioners Councel, That your Majeſty of your own Princely Prerogative, without any Declaration of the Lords, may Reſtore your Petitioner to his Birth-Right, Title, Honors, and Eſtate, that depends thereon.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>Your Petitioner therefore moſt humbly prays your Majeſty (in whom ſolely lies the Creation and preſervation of Honour and Nobi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity) to Declare your Royal pleaſure, for his Aſcending the Sphere and Dignity of his Anceſtors: Or, to graut unto your Petitioner (that hath groaned under Ten Years Oppreſſion without deciſion of his Claim) ſuch Yearly Penſion as may ſupport him, until his Cauſe come to a final Determination.</hi> And Your Petitioner ſhall Pray, <hi>&amp;c. JAMES PERCY.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:47799:6"/>THis Petition was preſented into your Majeſties Sacred Hand the 18. of <hi>December</hi> 1679. and Sir <hi>William Glaſcow,</hi> Maſter in waiting, order'd the Petitioner to call for an Anſwer the 22th. Inſtant, which the Petitioner accordingly did; but then found no opportunity to ſpeak with him: The Petitioner attended the 23. inſtant, and then Sir <hi>William</hi> returned this Anſwer by his Maid-Servant, <hi>That he was buiſie with ſome Friends, and that the King would hear nothing until after Chriſtmas-Eolidays.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That the Petitioner went to the Secretaries Office, to get this following <hi>Advertiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> to be entred into the <hi>Gazet,</hi> but it would not be allowed; which did much diſſatisfie your Majeſties Loyal Subject, to think that the True Heir, looking after his Birth-right, ſhould be put into the <hi>Gazet</hi> for an Impoſtor, when as he hath proved himſelf at the <hi>Court of Kings Bench,</hi> by <hi>Twelve</hi> honeſt Jury-men, to be the true <hi>Percy,</hi> and the only Heir-male to the Houſe of <hi>Northumberland.</hi> It is very ſad, when a <hi>lost Dog</hi> ſhall find Entrance into the <hi>Gazet,</hi> and a <hi>Juſt Man</hi> be kept out. The <hi>Adver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſement</hi> refuſed, is as follows.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="notice">
                        <head>Advertiſement.</head>
                        <p>
                           <hi>WHereas the Lord</hi> Ogle <hi>is publiſhed in print, to have changed his Name from</hi> Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vendiſh <hi>to</hi> Percy, <hi>upon his Marriage with the Lady</hi> Elizabeth Percy, James Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy <hi>
                              <abbr>Eſq</abbr> the true Heir-Male of the Blood of the Houſe of</hi> Northumberland, <hi>that hath ſtood to juſtify his Claim about Ten Years, and hath proved himſelf a Legitimate</hi> Percy <hi>in the Kings Bench, doth likewiſe publiſh to the world, that he will juſtify his Right</hi> durante vitae, <hi>and hopes the World will not be deceived by any Artifice; for he deſires no more but a free and final determination of his ſaid Claim.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Fiat Juſtitia &amp; ruat Coelum. <hi>James Percy.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>Notwithſtanding, your Loyal Petitioner verily believes your moſt Excellent Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty is much Miſ-inform'd, yet your Petitioner had not publiſhed this <hi>Advertiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi> had not he found my Lord <hi>Ogle</hi> to have changed his Name from <hi>Cavendiſh</hi> to <hi>Percy,</hi> printed in <hi>Mercurius Anglicus.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But now the Petitioner is reſolved, (like <hi>Heſter,</hi>) by Gods powerful Aſſiſtance, and your Majeſties gracious Acceptance, to ſtand up for the Name of <hi>Percy,</hi> as that Queen kneeled down to ſave her people.</p>
            <p>King <hi>Darius</hi> took <hi>Daniel</hi> out of the Lyons Den, and God (in a moſt Miraculous manner) Reſtored your Majeſty to your Kingdoms: And according to the Coronation<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>Oath, and your Majeſties Royal and Gracious Act of Free pardon and Indempnity, the Petitioner in Juſtice ought to be reſtored to his Birth-right and Title, or ſuch an Immediate Allowance as is uſual in ſuch Caſes, to keep the <hi>White-Horſe</hi> or <hi>Honour</hi> from ſtarving, until his Caſe be determined according to the prayer of the Petition.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Preſident the Lord</hi> Ogles <hi>Agents will inſiſt upon, is as followeth:</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>NOte,</hi> the Lady <hi>Agnes Percy,</hi> would not inter-marry with the Lord <hi>Joſceline De Lovaine,</hi> Son and Heir to the Duke of <hi>Brabant,</hi> the then Queen of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lands</hi> Brother, without he aſſumed her Name.</p>
            <p>The Reaſon was, There was not an Heir-Male then living of the <hi>Percies;</hi> There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore that was done purely to preſerve the Name of <hi>Percy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But now my Cozen (the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percies</hi> Caſe) is not the ſame: For the Heirs-Males of the <hi>Percies</hi> are not dead, as by the Claymants printed Book appears.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="notice">
                        <p>
                           <hi>But the Mystery of aſſuming the Name of Percy, is as follows</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>AS is the Settlement of <hi>Arundel</hi>-Caſtle, even ſo is the Settlement of the Honour of <hi>Petworth</hi> and <hi>Cockermouth,</hi> and divers other Lands, upon the Heirs-Males of the <hi>Percies</hi> for ever: And all thoſe Lands ſo Settled, and in the Crown, the Rents and Fines can be Recovered no wayes, but under the Name of <hi>Percy;</hi> and the Tenants have over-thrown the Ladies Agents at two ſeveral Tryals upon the ſame Acount.</p>
                        <p>The Petitioner commits this Cauſe to the Kingsmoſt Excellent Majeſty, the Parliament, and Leige People of <hi>England,</hi> to judge whether or no this be a Fraud intended, or not? Therefore, I humbly beg your Majeſties Pardon: For as the Petitioner, hath often demanded the Fines and Rents of the Tenants, and they durſt not obey, by reaſon his Pedigree was not then proved: But now his Pedigree is proved, to be the true Heir-Male of the Blood and Family of the <hi>Percies</hi> of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> that they ſtop all their Rents in their hands, and Prepare thoſe Fines that have been a long time kept from the true Heir-Male.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <pb facs="tcp:47799:6"/>
                  <head>To the Right Honourable Lords Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual and Temporal in Parliament Aſſembled.</head>
                  <q>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                        <body>
                           <div type="petition">
                              <head>The Humble Petition of <hi>JAMES PERCY.</hi>
                              </head>
                              <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                              <p>THat this is the 11th. year of the Petitioner's Claim to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                                    <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                                 </gap> and Eſtate belonging to the Earldom of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                              </p>
                              <p>That your Petitioner hath had ſeveral Tryals at Law, where he is pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved a true <hi>Percy</hi> legitimate, and no Impoſtor, as once a <hi>Gazer</hi> publiſhed.</p>
                              <p>That through the high Priviledges, Policy and Potency of the Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponents, and Treachery of his Solicitor, and falling area y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> of ſome of his Councel; all which occaſioned Errors both particular and general.</p>
                              <p>That as <hi>William Percy,</hi> the Brother of the Claimant, was out up to ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruct Proceedings; and now <hi>Francis Percy</hi> Stone. Cutter is cryed up, who declared himſelf to be the Grandſon of <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> that was in the <hi>Gun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powder-Plot,</hi> down in truth was the Son of <hi>Robert Percy,</hi> the Petitioner's great Uncle.</p>
                              <closer>
                                 <signed>
                                    <hi>He therefore prays, That a ſet day may be appointed, allowing</hi> 14 <hi>days time to ſummon in Witneſſes, ſo that the Pedigree may be fully proved, that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                                          <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                                       </gap> true Deciſion may be made according to Juſtice, and that Truth may be preſerved, and Errors corrected. And your Petitioner ſhall ever pray,</hi> &amp;c. JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                              </closer>
                           </div>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                  </q>
                  <p>THat whereas the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty hath been graciouſly pleaſed to refer the Petitioner's Cauſe to the Lords Spiritual and Temporal in Parliament, to Hear and Determine his ſaid Claim to the Earldom of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>That the Right Honourable Lords were pleaſed to receive the above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned Petiition of <hi>James Percy</hi> the Claimant, at the Bar of the ſaid Houſe of Lords the 17th of <hi>November</hi> 1680.</p>
                  <p>That your Lordſhips will be further graciouſly pleaſed, to Call for the ſaid Petition, and cauſe it to be Read, and appoint a day for Tryal, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Prayer of the aforeſaid Petition, ſo that the Pedigree of your Petitioner may be fully Tryed, with the two Writs of Error.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>
                        <hi>And your Petitioner ſhall ever pray,</hi> &amp;c. JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:7"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="order">
                        <head>
                           <hi>Die</hi> Jovis, 25. <hi>Novembris,</hi> 1680.</head>
                        <p>WHereas JAMES PERCY <abbr>Eſq</abbr> hath brought two <hi>Writs of Errour</hi> into this Houſe; In One of which, the ſaid JAMES PERCY is Plaintiff, and <hi>John Blackſtone</hi> 
                           <abbr>Eſq</abbr> is Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant: And in the other, <hi>Robert Utting</hi> is Plaintiff, and Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi> is Defendant; Upon both which <hi>Writs,</hi> the <hi>Errors</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing aſſigned, and Iſſue joyned: It is this Day Ordered by the Lords Spiritual and Temporal in PARLIAMENT Aſſembled, That this Houſe will hear the <hi>Errors</hi> upon the ſaid <hi>Two Writs of Errour</hi> Reſpectively, Argued by Councel at the BAR on both Parts, on <hi>Thurſday</hi> the 9th. Day of <hi>December</hi> next at <hi>Ten</hi> of the Clock in the Forenoon. Whereof the ſaid <hi>John Blakeſtone,</hi> and Sir <hi>John Coppleſtone</hi> reſpectively, are to cauſe Timely Notice to be given to the ſaid JAMES PERCY for that Purpoſe.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>JOHN BROWNE, <hi>Cleric' Parliamentor'</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>The Councel's Opinion, to prove the</hi> Pedigree, <hi>manifeſts</hi> Errours, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moves, Miſtakes <hi>and</hi> Scandals; <hi>and makes a clear way to</hi> Juſtice.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Therefore the following</hi> Pedigree <hi>is prepar'd for the Right Houourable Lords Spiritual and Temporal in</hi> Parliament <hi>at the Day of Hearing.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:7"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:8"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:8"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the Kings Moſt Excellent MAJESTY.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>James Percy.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                        <p>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HAT this is the 11th. Year of Your Petitioners Claim to the Title and Earldom of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That the 9th. Inſtant at 10. of the Clock, is appointed the day of Hearing, before the Right Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Lords Spiritual and Temporal in Parliament Aſſembled.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Therefore he moſt humbly Prays, that Your Majesty would be graciouſly pleaſed to be preſent at the hearing of the Cauſe, and then Your <hi>Majeſty</hi> will underſtand how the <hi>Moon</hi> hath been ſet under the horrid <hi>Black Cloud</hi> of Oppreſsion, and to ſee the <hi>Moon</hi> riſe into the Serene Horoſcope of Juſtice. And Your Petitioner ſhall Pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:9"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <pb n="1" facs="tcp:47799:9"/>
                        <head>To the King's moſt Excellent Majeſty.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>James Percy,</hi> Couſin, and next Heir-Male of <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> late and Eleventh Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Deceaſed.</head>
                        <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
                        <p>THat Your Petitioner hath about Ten Years, waited for the Juſtice of the Laws of Your Kingdom, at his Vaſt Charge; and ſtill at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tends the Iſſue of his Claim. And being informed, that the Lord <hi>Ogle</hi> is endeavouring an In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt, to get an Act of Parliament, for Settling the Lands of that Earldom upon him, under the Name of <hi>Percy.</hi> And Your Majeſty having always decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red Your Royal Pleaſure, That <hi>You</hi> would not wrong an Innocent Heir: And <hi>Henry</hi> the Fourth Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and <hi>John Nevell</hi> Lord <hi>Mountague,</hi> being Preſidents of Reſtitution, when in Default.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>Your Petitioner moſt Humbly prayes, and hopes Your Gracious Majeſty will be pleaſed to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider his Caſe; and of Your Royal VViſdom and Juſtice, to Reſtore him to the State and Dignity of his Anceſtors; having proved him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf at Law, a True</hi> Percy, <hi>of the Family and Blood of the Houſe of</hi> Northumber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land. And Your Petitioner ſhall Pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:47799:10"/>THis Petition was Preſented into the <hi>King</hi>'s Sacred Hand, the 25th. of <hi>November,</hi> 1679. and the Maſter in waiting, his Account was much like to that of Sir <hi>John Berkenſheds.</hi> So the Claymant's Caſe lies wholly before the Parliament. And therefore, moſt humbly prayes, That if the Lord <hi>Ogle</hi> goes on, and prevails in their Act of Parliament, that there may be a Saving put into that Act, for <hi>James Percy,</hi> the now Claymant, and his Heirs; according to the <hi>King</hi>'s Gracious Direction.</p>
            <p>Moreover, That the Right Honourable, the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, will be graciouſly pleaſed to call the Pedigree of the Claymant before them; and according to a Verdict exempli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fyed under the Seal of his Majeſties Court of <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench,</hi> to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port. So that, the <hi>King</hi>'s moſt Excellent Majeſty may be fully ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfyed; and the Claymant, <hi>James Percy,</hi> may at laſt be Reſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to the Place and Seat of his Anceſtors, Earls of <hi>Northum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Do Juſtice; Remove Oppreſſion; Then <hi>GOD</hi> will Bleſs our <hi>King,</hi> Parliament, and People, to the Amazement of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi>'s Enemies, and Joy to all his Majeſties Loyall Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects.</p>
            <p>All New Matters are ſtill plac'd in the Front of this Book, as the Directions further cites to.</p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <pb n="1" facs="tcp:47799:10"/>
                  <head>TO HIS GRACE, THE High-Born Prince, JAMES, Duke of York.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Great Sir,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>I Have Petitioned your Royal Brother, our Gracious KING, to be Admitted to ſpeak a few words: And in the like Nature, Petitioned your Grace; but was not Heard.</p>
                  <p>Therefore, I have made bold to Print; and prays your Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tient Peruſal, and to Act for Juſtice.</p>
                  <p>☞ <hi>Juſtice</hi> will ſtop my Pen, and turn my Complaints into Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers and Thankfulneſs.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>James Percy.</signed>
                     <dateline>
                        <hi>London,</hi> 
                        <date>
                           <hi>Octob.</hi> 21. 1679.</date>
                     </dateline>
                  </closer>
                  <postscript>
                     <p>Potent Adverſary's Practiſes, prevents my Opportunities: For I had purpoſed, by <hi>God</hi>'s Aſſiſtance, and Your Gracious Acceptance, to have Preſented the Book my ſelf; and hop'd to obtain'd the Honor, to Kiſt Your Graces Hand.</p>
                  </postscript>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <list>
               <head>This is a further Addition of what hath been done ſince the former Additions was added to this Printed Book; and ſomething of Moment, which was formerly left out.</head>
               <item>1. A Petition to the KING, and Houſe of Lords.</item>
               <item>2. A Petition to the Houſe of Commons.</item>
               <item>3. A Letter to a Gentleman, that did pretend he could prevail much with the Counteſs.</item>
               <item>4. A Letter to the Lord <hi>Ogle:</hi> With other Arguments and Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons.</item>
            </list>
            <q>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:47799:11"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the KING's most Excellent Majeſty, and the Right Honorable, the Lords Spiritual and Temporal.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>James Percy,</hi> Couſin, and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> late Earl of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
                        <p>THat Your Petitioner put in his Claym, as Heir to the Title, Honors, Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the <hi>Percies,</hi> as Rightfully and Legitimately De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcended of the Antient and Noble Houſe, Nine Years ago; and ſtill continueth the ſame, in hopes that he may have Juſtice done him.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>And therefore Humbly prayes Your Majesty, and Your Lordſhips, to hear and determine his Right, having proved himſelf a True</hi> Percy <hi>at Law.</hi> And he ſhall Pray, <hi>&amp;c. James Percy.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>This Petition to the King, and Houſe of Lords, was Preſented the 17th. of <hi>October,</hi> 1679. Mr. <hi>Walker</hi> the Clark ſaid, That nothing of Private Concerns would be received that Day.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the Right Honourable, the Knights, Citizens, and Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſſes, in Parliament Aſſembled.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>James Percy,</hi> Couſin, and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>line Percy,</hi> late Earl of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
                        <p>THat Your Petitioner having Nine Years claimed, and induſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly proſecuted his Right to the Honors, Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Houſe of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> and not yet been able to obtain a Definitive Sentence, by reaſon of the Potency of his Adverſaries, and the Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> (as your Petioner is informed) indeavouring to carry away the ſaid Honor, upon his Marriage with the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>Your Petitioner humbly prayes the Benefit of his Birth-Right, and an Engliſh-Man, to be heard to his Claim, before any Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluſive Bar by Act of Parliament.</hi> And your Petitioner ſhall Pray, <hi>&amp;c. James Percy.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>This Petition to the Houſe of Commons would have been Preſented the ſame Day; but one of the Clarks ſaid, It was not proper to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver it, till the Speaker was Choſen.</p>
            <p>As the Claymant feared, the other Proroguement would have done him Harm; ſo this laſt Prorogation tends to his Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage: For he hath now time to go for <hi>Ireland,</hi> to Inform, Incourage,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:47799:11"/>and Direct his Eldeſt Son, <hi>Anthony Percy,</hi> to ſtand up to maintain the Claim of his Father; Who declares, if any thing ſhould happen o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe than well, or that he ſhould Dye, he is the next Heir ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parent; and if his Iſſue fail, then to his Second Brother, <hi>Henry Percy;</hi> and if his Iſſue fails, then to <hi>John Percy,</hi> the Youngeſt Son, and his Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſue: And if it ſhall pleaſe <hi>God,</hi> the Claymant, his Sons, and Grand-Children ſhould all Dye; yet there are <hi>Percies</hi> enough, which was the Children of <hi>Robert Percy,</hi> Second Brother of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> the Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> and-Grand-Children of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Fi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> Earl of <hi>Northumberland:</hi> Which <hi>Henry</hi> and <hi>Robert,</hi> was ſent out of the <hi>North</hi> in Hampers, with two Siſters, to the Lady <hi>Vaux,</hi> in Queen <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lizabeths</hi> Days: And this the Claymant hath done, to prevent the Title, and the Eſtate of the <hi>Perices,</hi> from being Smugled any more, as at this day.</p>
            <p>Moreover, if His Majeſty will not give the Claymant Maintenance, nor appoint him a Match; yet it gives the Claymant opportunity to recruit again. As he intended to Print no more; ſo by <hi>God</hi>'s Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance, he ſhall never give over his Claim.</p>
            <p>The 15th. Day, the Claymant carryed his Falſe Pedigree, and the True Pedigree, to Sir <hi>William Dugdel</hi> again, and he did promiſe to ſtand up for Juſtice.</p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <head>This to a Gentleman, that did pretend to prevail much with the Counteſs.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>SIR,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>I <hi>Have Received my Loſt Son; He is found, and return'd again: All Praiſes be rendred to the Almighty God; who, in his good time, can ſend me Peace alſo: For He is Greater, than they that oppoſe me. We intend to viſit</hi> Bran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford, <hi>the Latter End of the next week, to ſee if you can perform your Promiſe to me: And, in the mean time, if you pleaſe to preſent this incloſed Book, with my moſt Humble Service, to the Counteſs</hi> Dowager <hi>of</hi> Northumberland; <hi>and tell her Honor, I would not have preſumed to have given her this Trouble, but only that Truth might be known, and to obtain a right Underſtanding.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Moreover, if her Honor will be graciouſly pleaſed to hear me ſpeak, I could Propound that, which would ſilence all our Differences.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>For I am like my Couſin</hi> Henry Hot Spur, <hi>who choſe to loſe his Life, rather than to yeild to that, which would abate his Honor and Reſolution.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>But when I find Juſtice founded upon the Baſis of Reaſon, then I ſhall, by God's Aſſiſtance, be found like a</hi> Jonathan <hi>to</hi> David. <hi>In the mean time, I remain</hi>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your very Loving Friend, <hi>James Percy.</hi>
                     </signed>
                     <dateline>
                        <hi>London,</hi> 
                        <date>June 14th, 1679.</date>
                     </dateline>
                  </closer>
                  <postscript>
                     <p>I Lodge at Mr. <hi>Curtis</hi> his Houſe, in <hi>Windſor-Court</hi> in <hi>Mugwell-Street,</hi> near <hi>Cripplegate.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <pb n="4" facs="tcp:47799:12"/>I Write not as an <hi>Harbenger,</hi> to prepare Proviſions, but as an <hi>Herauld,</hi> to proclaim Peace to the Counteſs, if ſhe pleaſe. For their Act of Parliament ſhall never paſs Both Houſes, without Juſtice be abſolute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Buried alive in this our Nation; <hi>Ezek.</hi> 46. Verſ. 18. Moreover, the Scripture ſaith, <hi>Curſe ye him, that removeth his Neighbor's Land-Mark.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </postscript>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <head>A Letter left at Suffolk-Houſe, for the Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> near Charing-Croſs.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>My Lord,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <hi>EVer ſince the year,</hi> 1670. <hi>I have applyed my ſelf not only in Perſon, but by Letters and Friends; as the Printed Lines ſets forth: And with two of my Youngeſt Sons, did upon the</hi> 24th <hi>of</hi> June, 1679. <hi>wait for an Anſwer; But found Things not Performed, as was expected.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Now, My Lord, by your Marrying my Couſin, the Lady</hi> Elizabeth Percy, <hi>you are become concerned: And ſince I can no ways come to the Speech of her</hi> Grand-Mother, <hi>be pleaſed, that I may ſpeak with</hi> you, <hi>of Differences paſt, and to prevent Differences to come.</hi> God <hi>direct you, even as he did King</hi> Solomon, <hi>and young</hi> Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niel, <hi>to do, Act, and ſtand up for Juſtice: For which, I have, and ſhall leave no ſtone unturn'd, till I find it. According to this incloſed Print, I am.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                     <salute>My Lord,</salute>
                     <signed>Your Honors moſt Humble Servant, <hi>James Percy.</hi>
                     </signed>
                     <dateline>
                        <date>June, 26. 1679.</date>
                     </dateline>
                  </closer>
                  <postscript>
                     <p>And Mr. <hi>Gee</hi> did declare to the Claymant, under <hi>White-Hall-Wall;</hi> That if they had thought, he had had an Eſtate to have Supported the Title withal, they would have Owned him long ago. If he had not been call'd from his Merchandizing, by God's Bleſſing, he might have obtained ſuch an Eſtate of his own, as would have preſerved a <hi>Percy</hi> from a <hi>Nevel</hi>'s Lot. For when <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Fourth Earl of <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland</hi> return'd, then was he Created Marqueſs <hi>Mountague.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Champion,</hi> that kept all the Records, confeſt, that there was a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove 4000 <hi>l. per annum,</hi> to attend the Title, before old Mr. <hi>Rogers</hi> dyed; and then <hi>Canington,</hi> and <hi>Rodaway</hi> Lands, return'd to the <hi>Percies</hi> again. And the Agents now hath no other way, but to endeavour the Lands may be ſetled by Act of Parliament upon the Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> in the Name of <hi>Percy.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>The true and real Intent of the Claymant, is to ſatisfy King and Parliament; ſo as Fraud may be prevented, and a Royal Writ of Summons may be had, to call him to that Seat and Place of his An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſtors, Earls of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>
                           <hi>James Percy</hi> (10 Years Claymant) prays for Juſtice.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </postscript>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <q>
               <pb n="*" facs="tcp:47799:12"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="notice">
                        <head>To the KING'S moſt Excellent Majeſty, the Right Honorable Lords, Spiritual and Temporal; and to the Noble and Worthy Commons of <hi>England,</hi> Aſſembled in <hi>Parliament.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>THis out-ſide Sheet was really prepared to add to this Book, to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deceive <hi>King, Parliament,</hi> and <hi>People;</hi> and to unmask the cunning Contrivances of Politicians, who Publiſhed the Claymant, <hi>James Percy,</hi> in the <hi>Gazet,</hi> to be an Impoſtor; ſetting forth a Pedigree of the Claymant's younger Brother, Mr. <hi>William Percy;</hi> pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to undeceive the People: But their real Deſign was, to wildernize the true Heir, and amuſe the World. Notwithſtanding, the Claymant hath at the laſt, proved himſelf the next Heir, as by a Judgment and Verdict; and reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered Coſt, as by the Verdict exemplyfied under the Seal of his Majeſty's Court of <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench:</hi> And therefore, with Courage, and a clear Soul, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands the Place and Seat of his Anceſtors, as the true Heir-Male of the <hi>Percies,</hi> and Earls of <hi>Northumberland.</hi> And therefore, the Lord <hi>Ogle</hi> (that Marryed the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy</hi>) ought not to Aſſume the Name of <hi>Percy,</hi> nor have any Settlement of the Lands, which attend the Title. For the Agents did put in a Bill to the Right Honorable Committee of the <hi>Houſe of Lords,</hi> to be made an Act of <hi>Parliament,</hi> for the Settlement of the ſaid Lands: And alſo, pretended to Indemnify the Truſtees, But it is rather judg'd, the real Contrivance of the Truſtees, was meerly to bring themſelves off, from giving an Account of the main Profits, and the great Waſts, that have been Committed ever ſince the Death of <hi>Joſceline,</hi> the late Earl of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> which on the <hi>Twenty-First</hi> of <hi>May</hi> next, will be Ten Years. Not many of the Perſecutions have been of that long Continuance.</p>
                        <p>An Act of <hi>Parliament</hi> may be ſooner ſtop't; but will be hard to Reverſe, though never ſo Illegally obtain'd.</p>
                        <p>This firſt Sheet, added to this Book, contains the laſt Petition to the <hi>King,</hi> and a ſhort Abſtract of the ſeveral Tryals.</p>
                        <p>The Laſt Sheet was an Account to one, that deſired to be ſatisfyed, by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon the Agents had miſ-informed him: But now he is really Convinced.</p>
                        <p>The Second Sheet was likewiſe prepared for the laſt Seſſion of <hi>Parliament,</hi> and ſets forth the ſeveral Petitions, Reaſons, and Tranſactions in the Late Par<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>liament. <hi>Pag.</hi> 1, 2, &amp; 13, 14.</p>
                        <p>The Three Sheets containing the middle of the Book, wherein he Petitioned the the <hi>Houſe of Commons</hi> for their Aid; not any wayes intending to Relinquiſh his Right in the <hi>Houſe of Peers.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>A Narrative of the ſeveral Tryals and Proceedings in the <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench,</hi> before my Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hayles,</hi> and the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Rainsford. Pag.</hi> 3.</p>
                        <p>The double Tryal, before the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Scroggs. Pag.</hi> 5.</p>
                        <p>A ſhort Abſtract of the Claymant's proceedings, ever ſince the Death of <hi>Jo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſceline Percy,</hi> late and Eleventh Earl of <hi>Northumberland. Pag.</hi> 9.</p>
                        <p>The Pedigree of <hi>James Percy,</hi> which proves him to be Couſin, and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſceline,</hi> the late Earl, and Heir-Male of the Body of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> the Fifth Earl of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> Deſcended from Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> his Younger Son, who was Innocent, and his Iſſue remains untainted to this Day. <hi>Pag.</hi> 12.</p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <pb n="**" facs="tcp:47799:13"/>THere was a Petition preſented to the <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Council:</hi> But the Reſult of the Board was, The Cauſe lay not before them, but before the <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And the Kings moſt Gracious Anſwer to the Claimants firſt Petition, was, <hi>God forbid, we ſhould hinder an Heir, but that he ſhould have the Benefit of the Law.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now, his Majeſties further Gracious Anſwer is, to this Laſt following Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tition, Preſented into his Majeſties ſacred Hand, the 21st. of <hi>September,</hi> 1679. as Sir <hi>John Birkenhead</hi> did inform the Petitioner, this 24th. Inſtant.</p>
            <p n="1">1. <hi>As to the Writ of Summons, to Sit in the Houſe of</hi> Peers, <hi>His Majeſty replyes, He cannot Grant it; by reaſon the Cauſe had been before the Houſe of</hi> Lords: <hi>And that it muſt be Determined by them, before his Majeſty could Grant the ſaid Writ of Summons.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. <hi>As for that Act of</hi> Parliament, <hi>the Lord</hi> Ogle <hi>was indeavoring to obtain; His Majeſty was further pleaſed to ſay, That the Petitioner might put in a</hi> Proviſo, <hi>that there might be a Saving to the Petitioner, and to his Heirs; as the Counſels learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in the Law, ſhould Adviſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the KING'S moſt Excellent Majeſty.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>James Percy.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
                        <p>THat Your Petitioner hath theſe Nine Years, induſtriouſly Proſecuted his Claim to the Titles, Honors, Priviledges, Mannors, and Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> that of Right deſcend to him, as Couſin and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſceline Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy,</hi> late and Eleventh Earl of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That there was a Bill preſented to the Right Honorable Committee of Lords, the laſt Seſſion of <hi>Parliament,</hi> for the Settling all thoſe Lands by an Act of <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament,</hi> that of right attends the Title and Name of your Petitioner, upon the Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> who Marryed the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> and would have Aſſumed her Name: Which Act would have cut off the Right of the Heir-Males of the <hi>Percies</hi> for ever.</p>
                        <p>Notwithſtanding, Your Petitioners clayming the ſaid Honors and Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as afore-ſaid; although his Claym hath not been determined theſe Nine Years, as above-ſaid; and now going on in the Tenth Year of his Claym.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>May it therefore pleaſe Your moſt Excellent Majeſty, to give Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand for Your Petitioner's Summons to this preſent <hi>Parliament;</hi> by reaſon Your Petitioner hath proved himſelf the next Heir-Male in Blood, to the <hi>Percies</hi> of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> as by a Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment and Verdict exemplyfied under the Seal of Your Majeſty's Court of <hi>King's-Bench.</hi> Moreover, The Extreams of the Law, which Your Majeſty was Graciouſly pleaſed to refer Your Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioner unto, and the Potency of the Defendants is ſuch, that it forces your Petitioner to fly to Your Royal Majeſty for Juſtice. <hi>And he ſhall ever Pray,</hi> &amp;c.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb n="***" facs="tcp:47799:13"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="abstract">
                        <head>A ſhort Abſtract of the ſeveral Tryals is here-unto Annexed, to ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfy Your Majeſty.</head>
                        <p>WHereas Your Majeſty was Graciouſly pleaſed, to leave Your Petitioner to the Law; therefore, the Petitioner humbly Preſents theſe few Lines, to ſhew what is proved by the Law.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Firſt Tryal</hi> in the Year 1674. The Petitioner was <hi>Plaintiff,</hi> againſt <hi>John Clark,</hi> 
                           <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                           <hi>Defendant,</hi> who was the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percies</hi> Agent, for ſcandalous Words he had ſpoken againſt the Plaintiff: At which Tryal Judge <hi>Hales</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared, That <hi>James Percy,</hi> the Claymant and Plaintiff, had proved himſelf a true <hi>Percy;</hi> Legitimate by Father and Mother, Grand-Father and Grand-Mother; and of the Blood and Family of the <hi>Percies</hi> of <hi>Northumberland:</hi> And he did ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rily believe, that Your Petitioner was Couſin, and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> the late and Eleventh Earl of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> only he was afraid, he had taken his Deſcent a little too low.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Second Tryal,</hi> was upon an Ejectment for <hi>Cannington</hi>-Lands in <hi>Somerſet-ſhire;</hi> which Lands of Right, fell to the Heirs-Males of the <hi>Percies,</hi> after the Heirs-Males of the <hi>Rogerſes</hi> was Extinct: Doubtleſs, it was by Miſ-information, that Your Majeſty was miſtaken in Your Gift. And at that Tryal, the Pedigree of Your Petitioner was fully proved; and the Plaintiff ought to have had a Verdict for the ſame: But Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi> being made Defendant in the Caſe, ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained 80 <hi>l.</hi> Coſt; and doth violently Proſecute the Claymant and Plaintiff, for the ſame. Notwithſtanding, the Defendants do wrongfully poſſeſs thoſe Lands, and receives the Profits; and preſerved themſelves all along by Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges, for many Years; to the utter Ruin of Your Petitioner, if not timely prevented by Your Sacred Majeſty.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Third Tryal,</hi> Your Petitioner proved himſelf Legitimate again; And not the Tyth of the Plaintiff's Witneſſes was Heard at that Tryal; by reaſon Judge <hi>Raynsford</hi> ſtood up, and ſaid, The Pedigree was ſufficiently proved by the For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer Tryals; as by the Judgment and Verdict exemplyfied under the Seal of Your Majeſty's Court of <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Fourth Tryal,</hi> the Plaintiff was forc'd to pay 90 <hi>l</hi> for <hi>Clark</hi>'s Coſt, before the Lord of <hi>Eſſex</hi>'s Priviledge could be got off, to go on to Tryal: And then the Defendant's Councel did declare in Court, That they did own the Plaintiff's Pedigree and Title; and yet would not ſuffer the Plaintiff's Writings to be Read, nor his Witneſſes to be Heard; which prevented the Plaintiff from re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covering the 10000 <hi>l.</hi> Damages, which was laid in the Declaration: And for want of Juſtice, the Plaintiff lieth under the Burden of an Eundred Marks Coſts. Which Tryal ought to be Reviewed, and the Plaintiff Relieved.</p>
                        <closer>He therefore Prays, and humbly Beſeeches Your moſt Excellent Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty, to remember Your own Troubles; how <hi>God</hi> delivered You out of the Oppreſſor's Hand: And even ſo be pleaſed to deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver Your oppreſſed Petitioner, out of the Hands of his Power<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Opponants; ſo that, at laſt, he may injoy his Birth-right in Peace, according to Juſtice.
And if the Petitioner be delayed longer, he muſt humbly pray Your Majeſty for Maintenance, as is uſual in ſuch Caſes, to ſupport him, till he hath Recovered his Right, Title and Inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritance <signed>And Your Petitioner ſhall further Pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <pb n="****" facs="tcp:47799:14"/>IT is Hop'd, that Your Majeſty will never Condeſcend, that the Lord <hi>Ogle</hi> ſhall aſſume the Name of <hi>Percy;</hi> nor that the <hi>Percies</hi> Lands ſhall be ſettled upon him, by Act of Parliament: For the Lady <hi>Lucy</hi> gave all her Lands to the Heir-Males of the <hi>Percies</hi> for ever. God forbid, that ever ſuch a Fraud ſhould be Committed in this Nation! Eſpecially, when the true Heir-Male hath pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved his Pedigree.</p>
            <p>Moreover, Your Petitioner remains Unmarryed: And further hopes, that by <hi>God</hi>'s Providence, and Your patron-like Care, ſuch a Match may be obtain'd, that will ſupport the Title, and raiſe the <hi>Percies</hi> Name to its former Splendor.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="notice">
                        <p>THE Proroguing the <hi>Parliament,</hi> till the <hi>Thirtyeth</hi> of <hi>October</hi> next, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces the Claymant to make this further Complaint: For its Conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence is as prejudicial, as Priviledges have been to the Plaintiff; and as much for the Advantage of the Agents and Defendants: Who by Priviledges, Delayes, and Oppreſſion, ſtill keeps Poſſeſſion; and the true Heir ſtill under Perſecution. For this Prorogument falls out as pat for the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants, as if it had been by their own Appointment. Had the <hi>Parliament</hi> held to Sit on the 17th. Day, then had the Claymant had time to have put in his Petition, in Obedience to the <hi>King</hi>'s Gracious Anſwer and Direction, to the Right Honorable Houſe of LORDS, to have been call'd into that Right Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Houſe of PEERS; To have taken the Place and Seat of his Noble Anceſtors, Earls of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> according to his Birth - right and Title; which would have been a Means to have prevented the Act of <hi>Parliament,</hi> for the ſettling <hi>Percies</hi> Lands upon the Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> that Marryed the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> and that he ſhould not Aſſume the Name of <hi>Percy;</hi> and that the Fraud intended, might be prevented. But now, the Oppreſſors have gain'd this fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing Advantage; The <hi>Term</hi> will be a Week old, by that time the <hi>Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> Sits: ſo that, they hope, in that time, to contrive the Claymant into a Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon; ſo that he ſhall not be able to attend the Houſe, when they Sit: If they obtain their Aims, then will the Claymant further Complain to the LORDS and COMMONS, by freſh Petitions. And in the mean time, he hath prepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red theſe Prints, to pre-admoniſh the World: And that Juſt Men may know, that <hi>James Percy</hi> is the true and lawful Heir; and of right, ought to enjoy the Earldom of <hi>Northumberland:</hi> and that the Eſtate muſt attend the Title. But cruel Oppreſſion ſtill keeps Poſſeſſion; which forces the Claymant, to cry out aloud, again, again, and again, for Juſtice: and that Property, and Right, may be preſerved. For if his Innocent, and Juſt Cauſe, ſhould be now neglected, your Children, and Children's Children, may be Rejected another Day. I pray <hi>God,</hi> to direct our <hi>King, Parliament,</hi> and <hi>People;</hi> that they may fore ſee Things ſo, as to preſerve the Cood, and prevent the Evils, to come.</p>
                        <closer>AMEN.</closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:14"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:15"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the Honorable, The <hi>KNIGHTS, CITIZENS,</hi> &amp; <hi>B<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RGESSES,</hi> Of The <hi>Houſe of Commons,</hi> IN PARLIAMENT Aſſembled.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>James Percy,</hi> 
                           <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
                        </head>
                        <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
                        <p>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hat it is now almoſt Nine Years, ſince he put in his Claym as Deſcended of the houſe of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and next Cozen and Heir-Male to <hi>Joſcelin</hi> late Earl of <hi>Northumberland:</hi> All which time he hath Vigorouſly and Induſtriouſly purſued his Right, though againſt ſo great and unequal Force and Oppoſition, that he hath not been able to prevail: And therefore humbly prayes Leave to bring the State of his Caſe, and the Narrative of his Proceedings, before this Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norable Houſe, Imploring their Aſſiſtance, to Appear, Mediate and Interpoſe, for his Relief:</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>And your Petitioner ſhall Pray,</hi> &amp;c.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:47799:15"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="narrative">
                        <head>A NARRATIVE OF THE PROCEEDINGS OF THE PETITIONER, Since His Petitions were Diſmiſſed by the Right Honorable, the Houſe of LORDS, and his Caſe left to the Law.</head>
                        <p>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N <hi>Trinity-Term,</hi> 1674. the Petitioner brought an Action in the <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench,</hi> againſt <hi>John Clarke,</hi> Eſquire, for Scandal and Defamation he had thrown upon your Petitioner: Where, upon Hearing, ſome of his Witneſſes did not appear. Nevertheleſs, your Petitioner went ſo far on with the Proof of his Pedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree, and Lineal Diſcent from the Earls of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> that the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hales,</hi> ſaid in open Court; That the Plaintiff (meaning your Petitioner) had proved himſelf a True <hi>Percy,</hi> of the Blood and Family of the <hi>Percies</hi> of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> legitimate by Father and Mother, Grand-Father and Grand-Mother; and that he did verily believe, your Petitioner was Couſin, and next Heir - Male of <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> late Earl of <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland:</hi> But was afraid, he had taken his Diſcent a little too Low; and willed him, to come better Prepared next Tryal. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon your Petitioner ſuffered a Non-ſuit. A
<note n="*" place="margin">
                              <p n="1">1. <hi>The Reaſon of the Miſtake in the Firſt Pedigree, was, that the Herald-Stainer left out Sr.</hi> Ingle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ram Percy, <hi>the Great Grand-Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther.</hi>
                              </p>
                              <p n="2">2. <hi>Search<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Herald-Stayner's Book, that had been lent out; the ſaid Book was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned, the Leaf where the Matches of the</hi> Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies <hi>Family were ſet down, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Alphabet, being torn out.</hi>
                              </p>
                              <p n="3">3. <hi>There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, his Counſel did adviſe to fix the Pedigree upon Sir</hi> Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy; <hi>and if he was found the Wrong, it would be the means to find out the Right; as it did effect, at laſt.</hi>
                              </p>
                           </note> Miſtake, I hope, all will Pardon, to one under thoſe Diſadvantages the Claimant was; who was forced to Abſcond in <hi>England</hi> for his Loyalty, (and Travel for ſome Years) and had not an Opportunity to aquaint himſelf
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:47799:16"/>with the Family of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> ſo as to be informed of his Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digree. The Truth is, When he came into <hi>England,</hi> to Claim his Honor and Eſtate; though he knew it was his Right, yet it was hard for him to prove his Great Grand-Father, as it would be for moſt (perhaps) that Condemn him,
<note n="2" place="margin">Search<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Herald-Stayner's Book, that had been lent out; the ſaid Book was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned, the Leaf where the Matches of the <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies</hi> Family were ſet down, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Alphabet, being torn out.</note> when a Family is ſo Diſperſed, and the Pedigree of the Younger Sons neglected by the Herald.</p>
                        <p>Upon a Second Action brought i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> 
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>e Court of the <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench,</hi> againſt Sir <hi>John Copleſton,</hi> Truſtee fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> 
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                              <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                           </gap> Lady <hi>Clifford;</hi> Sir <hi>John</hi> ſhel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred himſelf under the Priviledge, ſo long as he could: When he was forced to a Tryal, your Petitioner proved himſelf Couſin, and next Heir-Male of the ſaid <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> late Earl of <hi>Northum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland,</hi> as followeth; For, the Claimant, <hi>James Percy,</hi> was the Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Grand-Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Eſquire, Great Grand-Son of Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> Great great Grand-Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Fifth Earl of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> So as the Court willed him to proceed to the Title of the Lands: Unto which his Counſel replyed; That the Lands muſt attend the Title; That the Deeds, Evidences Books of Entries, and the Records of the Eſtate were in the Poſſeſſion of the Defendants. So that, at preſent, they were not prepared nor in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructed to proceed further than the Legitimation, and Lineal Diſcent of your Petitioner,
<note n="3" place="margin">There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, his Counſel did adviſe to fix the Pedigree upon Sir <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy;</hi> and if he was found the Wrong, it would be the means to find out the Right; as it did effect, at laſt.</note> from the Noble Family of the Earls of <hi>Northum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That upon the Thirteenth of <hi>June,</hi> 1676. your Petitioner brought his Action in <hi>Guild-Hall, London,</hi> againſt <hi>John Blackeſton,</hi> Eſquire, for Scandal and Defamation: But the Defendant moved the Court of <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench,</hi> that the Action might be removed, and brought into that Court: And that a Tryal might be there had; which was ordered accordingly. And the Seventh of <hi>May</hi> they appointed to Hear the Cauſe: The Petitioner humbly ſubmitted to the Pleaſure of the Court. And your Petitioner, and the Defendant, having ſome few Weeks before the ſaid Time of the Tryal, by Conſent, attended the Maſter of the Office, and ſettled a <hi>Jury:</hi> Your Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioner prepared for a Tryal, and brought up from many, and ſome very remote Parts of the Kingdom, Sixty-five Witneſſes, all in Court; whoſe Travels to and fro, upon Calculation, amounted to above Four Thouſand Miles; and had Fourteen Learned Councels at the Bar: The Charges of all amounting to about Four Hundred Pound. And thus prepared, brought on the Cauſe to a Hearing the Day appointed: When imediately the Defendant's Counſel inſiſted upon the Priviledge of the <hi>Counteſs Dowager</hi> of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> in Protecting her Servants and Agents; The ſaid <hi>John Blackeſton</hi> being Steward of her Courts, and pretended Receiver of her Rents; and that he was upon the ſaid Imployment. Whereupon all your Petitioner's Counſels refuſed to Plead, although the Court would have Heard them, and proceeded to Tryal of the Cauſe: But the Councel re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed, They had no mind to go to the <hi>Tower;</hi> ſome of them having been there before. And thus the Tryal was put off.</p>
                        <p>Whereupon Mr. <hi>Justice Wilde</hi> (hearing theſe Things) ſtood up, and ſaid in open Court; <hi>Fye, fye, Gentlemen! Is this a Time to inſiſt upon Priviledges? when you forced the Plaintiff to a Tryal, and have
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:47799:16"/>put him to ſo great Expence, Travel, and Labor? You do but cast Cold Water upon your Cauſe. It is not the firſt time this Cauſe hath been be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore this Court.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>When Mr. <hi>Blackeſton</hi> was asked, Whether he went to <hi>London,</hi> to look after <hi>Percy</hi>'s Tryal? he ſaid, It concerns me not; for the Counteſs of <hi>Northumberland</hi> is to bear me Harmleſs.</p>
                        <p>Upon the <hi>Fourteenth</hi> of <hi>May,</hi> 1678. there was a Tryal had at the <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench-Bar, Weſtminſter,</hi> for Scandalizing the Petitioner's Right and Title; where-on a Verdict was given for <hi>Three Hundred</hi> Pound Dammages to the Petitioner, and Judgment obtained there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on: As by the ſaid Judgment, exemplifyed under the Seal of the Court, appears.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Laſtly,</hi> That your Petitioner hath been all a-long perplexed and troubled by many Suits at Law, unjuſtly Commenced againſt him by the Agents of the Defendants, or ſome of them; on purpoſe to Tire him out, and Ruin him by Chargeable Defences: For it is now almoſt Eight Years, ſince he began his Claim. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, Humbly prayes this moſt High and Honourable Court, to open ſome way for the Hearing and Determination of this his Juſt Claim; as it ſhall in your Mature Wiſdoms ſeem meet and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient, for the Preſerving Property and Right.</p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="complaint">
                        <head>This further Complaint ſince the Late <hi>PARLIAMENT</hi> was Prorogued and Diſſolved.</head>
                        <p>Percy <hi>is Plaintiff;</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Blackeſton <hi>the Defendant.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>In Banco Regis, Mich. Term.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>MR. <hi>Blackeſton</hi> being Steward to the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> and the Counteſs <hi>Dowager</hi> of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> being her Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian; the ſaid <hi>Blackeſton</hi> ſtood upon the Counteſſes Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge; until, upon another Occaſion, the Duke of <hi>Monmouth,</hi> by an Order of the Houſe of LORDS, took off the Counteſſes Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges, as to the Guardian-ſhip.</p>
                        <p>Then Mr. <hi>Blackeſton</hi> ſheltered himſelf under the Earl of <hi>Eſſexes</hi> Priviledge; until the Plaintiff put his Petition into the Houſe of LORDS, that Mr. <hi>Blackeston</hi> might not be Priviledged by the ſaid Earl.</p>
                        <p>Upon which, the Earl agreed with the Plaintiff's Counſel, That if the <hi>Ninety</hi> Pound Coſts, that was unpaid upon the Non-ſuit be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween <hi>Percy</hi> Plaintiff, and <hi>Clarke</hi> Defendant, were paid; that then Mr. <hi>Blackeſton</hi> ſhould not ſtand upon Priviledge, but go to a Tryal; which he accordingly did, in his Majeſtie's Court of <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench.</hi> Before which time, in the ſaid Term, the Plaintiff's Councel infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med the Court, what the Earl had agreed unto.</p>
                        <p>
                           <pb n="6" facs="tcp:47799:17"/>Then the <hi>Lord Chief Justice</hi> ſtood up, and ſaid to the Plaintiff; That the Earl of Eſſex did promiſe upon his Honor, to ſet aſide his Priviledge; and that the Plaintiff ſhould have a Tryal againſt Mr. <hi>Blackeſton</hi> this Term, if the Plaintiff paid Mr. <hi>Clarke</hi>'s Coſts firſt: And we do promiſe, the Plaintiff ſhall have a fair Tryal.</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff thereupon paid the ſaid <hi>Ninety</hi> Pound Coſts into the Court accordingly.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Monday</hi> the Eleventh of <hi>November,</hi> the Plaintiff brought on his Tryal: The Declaration being read, Counſellor <hi>Scroggs</hi> opened the Cauſe; and upon a Word in the Declaration, there was ſome De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bate: But it was waved, the Declaration allowed, and the Scanda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous VVords in the Declaration proved.</p>
                        <p>Mr. <hi>Atturney General</hi> moved, that the VVitneſſes might be heard, to prove the Pedigree upward; it being the better way to Satis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fy the <hi>Court,</hi> and to Inform the <hi>Jury:</hi> And withal, ſaid; That his Clyant had no better way to prove his Pedigree, but by his Action of Slander: For he hath delivered Declarations in Ejectment, in ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Countries; and the Lands are all in great Perſons Hands, which ſtill delay him by Priviledges. Then was the Pedigrees delivered to the Judges.</p>
                        <p>But the <hi>Lord Chief Juſtice</hi> ſaid; What need we trouble the Court, to Examine all theſe Witneſſes, if there be no Lands? Therefore, let us ſee firſt, what Lands there are, to make good the Declaration. The Plaintiff produced Records out of the <hi>Tower,</hi> and other Places; which made out, That the Lady <hi>Lucies</hi> Lands in <hi>Cumberland,</hi> and other Countries, were ſettled upon the Heirs-Males of the <hi>Percies</hi> for ever, upon the Payment of <hi>Three Hundred</hi> Pound to the KING, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and Quartering the ſaid <hi>Lucies</hi> Coat of Arms with the <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Here the Defendant's Counſel ſtarted up an Attainder, which the Plaintiff's Counſel was not ready to Anſwer; the Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff's Sollicitor having made no Proviſion againſt the ſaid Attainder; being confident, that Attainder could not Hurt nor Prejudice the Tryal. And this cauſed the <hi>Jury</hi> to be with-drawn.</p>
                        <p>The <hi>Jury</hi> appeared three ſeveral Times in this Cauſe; which was occaſioned by the Delayes and Priviledges, which the Defendant ſheltred himſelf under. The Plaintiff payd all the <hi>Jury,</hi> and the <hi>Ninety</hi> Pound was to be continued in Court, till there had been a Fair Tryal: But upon a Motion of the Defendant's Counſel, there was a Peremptory Rule granted, to take the Mony out of Court; which was accordingly paid to the Defendant.</p>
                        <p>The Second Part of the Tryal ſhould have been had in <hi>Michael<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maſs-Term,</hi> 1678. while the Witneſſes were in Town: But the Tryal of Mr. <hi>Stayley</hi> prevented it; So that, the Plaintiff's Tryal was put off till <hi>Hillary-Term</hi> following, <hi>viz.</hi> 27th. <hi>January,</hi> 1678.</p>
                        <p>The Defendant's Counſel moved the Court the firſt Day of <hi>Hil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lary-Term,</hi> for a New <hi>Jury,</hi> and a longer Time; pretending, they had but Seven dayes Notice: When in Truth, the Defendant's Atturney had a Months Notice by the Plaintiff, and Twelve dayes No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice by the Plaintiff's Atturneys Clark. Upon which the Court
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:47799:17"/>gave a Rule for Seven dayes longer, and for a New <hi>Jury;</hi> which was Appointed accordingly.</p>
                        <p>Then the Defendant's Counſel afterwards moved the Court for a longer Day, by reaſon that their Writings were miſ-placed by the Fire in the Temple; which further Day was granted, till <hi>Thurſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day,</hi> the Sixth of <hi>February;</hi> and no Coſts conſidered to the Plaintiff, for keeping his Witneſſes in Town all that Time, notwithſtanding the Plaintiff's Counſel moved for Coſts.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note,</hi> The <hi>Lord Chief Justice Hales,</hi> in the Caſe of <hi>Percy</hi> Plaintiff, and <hi>Clarke</hi> Defendant: The Defendant's Counſel moved the Court for Seven Dayes time, pretending they were not Prepared: And the Rule of Court was to pay <hi>Thirty-Five</hi> Pound to the Plaintiff, to maintain his Witneſſes in Town for that time; which was paid.</p>
                        <p>Now, on the Sixth of <hi>February,</hi> 1678. the Tryal came on again: The New <hi>Jury</hi> did appear; the Declaration was read; and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellor <hi>Scroggs</hi> opened the Cauſe, as he did before. And one of the Witneſſes was called to prove the Words: And when he appeared, the Court acknowledged, he had proved the VVords ſufficiently be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore. And the Defendant's Counſel made no Objection againſt the Declaration.</p>
                        <p>So the Tryal was to go on, where it broake off: The Records of the Patents in Queen <hi>Maries</hi> time; one for the Barony, and the other for the Earldom, produced: And he that was the Clark, that Examined them, appeared; but was not ſuffered to prove them up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Oath.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note,</hi> The afore-ſaid Clark of the Rolls not appearing upon the laſt Tryal, was the Cauſe of with-drawing the <hi>Jury.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Then when the Court ſaw the Plaintiff was ready to Anſwer to their Objections, declared, That the Plaintiff was Deſcended Para<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mount the Attainders: And did own, the Attaint could not hurt the Plaintiff.</p>
                        <p>Then Mr. <hi>Atturney General</hi> moved, as at the firſt Part of the Try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al, That the VVitneſſes might be Examined, to prove the Pedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree.</p>
                        <p>VVhereupon, the Defendant's Counſel ſtarted up an Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, concerning the Exchange of Lands, between King <hi>Henry</hi> the <hi>Eighth,</hi> and <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> the <hi>Sixth</hi> Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and others.</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff's Counſel replyed; Here is the ſame Act, with ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Savings: That Saving of the Lady <hi>Lucies</hi> Lands was read, till it came to Sir <hi>John Melton.</hi> Then</p>
                        <p>The <hi>Lord Chief Justice</hi> replyed; This doth not concern you: There are no Lands, but are all given away by that Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff humbly replyed; The <hi>Melton</hi>'s could not Claim, ſo long as there was an Heir-Male of the <hi>Percies</hi> living. And the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> keeps in Poſſeſſion of the Lady <hi>Lueies</hi> Lands; to which ſhe hath no Right, as ſhe is the Heir-Temale: For her Agents had Two Tryals againſt the Tennants, and ſhe was Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thrown
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:47799:18"/>in both. Therefore, the Plaintiff's VVitneſſes ought to be heard, that his Pedigree may be fully proved: This will waſh the Scandal clear off the Plaintiff, from that Brand of an Impoſture ſet forth in the <hi>Gazet;</hi> And preſent the Claimant's Cauſe fairly to the KING, and the Houſe of LORDS.</p>
                        <p>The <hi>Lord Chief Juſtice</hi> ſaid; VVhat will you prove the Pedigree for, when there are no Lands to ſupport the Title?</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff replyed; And what have we to do with Lands, if we do not prove the Pedigree?</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff prayed, That the Saving might be Read, concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing <hi>Somerſet-ſhire</hi> Lands; for which Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi> is Truſtee: VVhich Lands were beg'd of His Majeſty; and kept under pretence, that there is no Heir-Male of the <hi>Percies</hi> living. The Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> claimes no Right therein: But if ſhe were in Poſſeſſion of the Lands, ſhe would endeavour to keep them; as they do by the Lands, claim'd by the Plaintiff.</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff alſo prayed, The Record might be Read, concerning the Lands the Duke of <hi>Monmouth</hi> had Recovered at a Tryal, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Counteſs of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> under pretence, there was no Heir-Male of the <hi>Percies</hi> (which was not allowed by the Court to be read); although the Duke was pleaſed ſometime to ſay, He had no Right to thoſe Lands, if there was an Heir-Male of the <hi>Percies</hi> living.</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff produces the Patent of Reſtitution, in <hi>Edward</hi> the <hi>Sixth</hi>'s Time, to <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> the Son of Sir <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> that Rebelled. Likewiſe, the Two Patents of the New Creation, of the Barony and Earldom, to <hi>Thomas</hi> and <hi>Henry;</hi> Granted by King <hi>Philip,</hi> and Queen <hi>Mary.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>And an Act of Parliament, in Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi>'s Time; which Act, if it had been Read, it would have Encouraged the Plaintiff's Counſel, to have pleaded an Abatement to that Act, profuſely Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deſcended unto by <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Sixth Earl of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> in the Time of King <hi>Henry</hi> the <hi>Eighth,</hi> when the ſaid Earl had no Heirs-Males of his own Body.</p>
                        <p>Two Orders of the Houſe of LORDS: The Firſt in King <hi>Charles</hi> the <hi>First,</hi> his Dayes: Then Reſolved upon the Queſtion, <hi>Nemine Contradicente;</hi> That no Perſon, that hath any Honor in him, and a Peer, may Alien, or Transfer the Honour to any other Perſon. Reſolved, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> That no Peer of this Realm can Drown or Extin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſh his Honor, (but that it Deſcend to his Deſcendants) neither by Surrender, Grant, Fine, nor any other Conveyance to the KING.</p>
                        <p>The <hi>Second</hi> in King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second's Time; Reſolved, and Adjudged, That no Fine Levied, or at any time here-after to be Levied to the King, can barr ſuch Titles of Honor, or the Right of any Perſon, claiming ſuch Title under him, that Levied, or ſhall Levy ſuch Fine.</p>
                        <p>Moreover;
<note place="margin">Charles 2d. <hi>Act of Obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vion.</hi>
                           </note> The KING's Gracious Act of Free Pardon, Oblivion, and Indempnity at <hi>Breda;</hi> If it Extended to <hi>Rebels,</hi> then well may <hi>Royaliſts</hi> claim their Birth-rights.</p>
                        <p>
                           <pb n="9" facs="tcp:47799:18"/>By the Pedigree from <hi>Henry,</hi> the Firſt Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> to <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> the Eleventh Earl of <hi>Northumberland:</hi> After every Rebellion in the Head-Line, there were ſtill New Creations and New Reſtitutions in Blood, to the Heirs-Males of the Head-Line, that was Attainted: If ſo, then great Reaſon the Collateral Line, that proves Innocent; ſhould claim their Birth-Right, after the Head-Line is ſpent. Therefore, it is requiſite, the Pedigree ſhould be fully proved up to his Great-Grand-Father.</p>
                        <p>The Defendant's Counſel replyed; We own your Pedigree, and your Title: But would not ſuffer any more of the Writings to be Read, nor the Witneſſes to be Examined.</p>
                        <p>The Plaintiff replyed; What will the Owning ſignify, if you will not ſuffer him to prove his Pedigree? If you will not exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine the Witneſſes, be pleaſed to Confirm what you own, by a Rule in Court.</p>
                        <p>The <hi>Lord Chief Juſtice</hi> thereupon ſaid; Confirm, or not Confirm, the Declaration is naught: Diſcharge <hi>Blackeſton</hi> from the Suit of <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy.</hi> Whereupon the Plaintiff was Non-ſuited: And the Coſts are Taxed to 100. Marks, without any Conſideration of the Plaintiff's vaſt Charge he was put to, by the Defendant's Delayes, and Put<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings-off by Priviledges: As by this, and the former Tryals doth appear.</p>
                        <p>☞ <hi>And the Plaintiffs own Counſel are of Opinion; That there is no Relief in this Caſe at Law, but by Act of Parliament: And therefore, hath prepared his Bill; And prayes, It may find Admittance.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="abstract">
                        <head>A Short <hi>ABSTRACT</hi> of the <hi>Claymant's</hi> Proceedings ever ſince the Death of <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> late Earl of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p n="1">1. UPon the 11th. of <hi>October,</hi> 1670. the Claymant Landed in <hi>England:</hi> Firſt applyed himſelf to the <hi>Senior</hi> Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſs <hi>Dowager</hi> of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> And ſhe was pleaſed, to ſend him to the <hi>Junior</hi> Counteſs: And then it was Reported, ſhe was with Child.</p>
                        <p n="2">2. The Claymant did then forbear, till Time made out to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary. And on the <hi>Third</hi> Day of <hi>February,</hi> 1671. he put in his Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veat and Claym, as followeth:</p>
                        <q>
                           <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                              <body>
                                 <div type="claim">
                                    <p>James Percy, <hi>
                                          <abbr>Eſq</abbr> as Cozen, and next Heir-Male of the Right Hono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable</hi> Joſceline <hi>Lord</hi> Percy, <hi>and Earl of</hi> Northumberland, <hi>lately Deceaſed, doth Claym the Title, Stile, Honor, and Dignity of Baron</hi> Percy, <hi>and Earl of</hi> Northumberland, Cum pertinentijs; <hi>and the Annual Rent or Fee of Twenty Pound, where-with the ſaid Dignity and Honor was, and is Endowed, payable by the</hi> Sheriff <hi>of</hi> Northumberland, <hi>out of the ſame County: And humbly deſires a Legal Tryal of his Right herein; and that no Grant in the</hi> interim <hi>may be made thereof, being his Inheritance and Birth-Right. Dated under my Hand, this Third Day of</hi> February, 1671.</p>
                                    <closer>
                                       <signed>JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                                       <hi>Copia Vera,</hi> Entred into the <hi>Signet-Office,</hi> at <hi>White-Hall.</hi>
                                    </closer>
                                 </div>
                              </body>
                           </floatingText>
                        </q>
                        <p n="3">
                           <pb n="10" facs="tcp:47799:19"/>3. He met with Mr. <hi>Henry Champion,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Orlando Gee,</hi> at Dr. <hi>Lamplughs;</hi> and pray'd them, to inform him of his Great-Grand-Father: But they rather took Advantage of his Ignorance. But, Mr. <hi>Henry Champion</hi> did very honeſtly upon his Oath, at Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi>'s Tryal, declare, That Sir <hi>Inglexam Percy</hi> was Marryed, and had Sons and Daughters; which did not only time, but fix the Clay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mant's Pedigree. Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy</hi> being left out of the Firſt Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digree, did much Wildernize the Claymant.</p>
                        <p n="4">4. The Claymant petitioned the KING, and his Gracious Anſwer was; <hi>God Forbid, we ſhould hinder an Heir; but that he ſhould have the Benefit of the Law.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p n="5">5. Alſo, he Applyed himſelf to the Earl <hi>Marſhal,</hi> ſuppoſing to have been Relieved by the Court of Honor; but his Expectations fail'd there.</p>
                        <p n="6">6. Then he Applyed himſelf to the LORDS, Spiritual and Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poral, Aſſembled in Parliament; and they likewiſe, upon the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Sir <hi>Francis pemberton,</hi> Serjeant at Law, Counſellor for the Plaintiff, diſmiſt his Petitions; and ſo he was left to the Law.</p>
                        <p n="7">7. Then his Sollicitor adviſed the Claymant, (by reaſon the Court of Wards was Diſſolved by an Act of Parliament, 12. <hi>Car.</hi> 2. c. 24.) to Sue by way of <hi>Quo Warranto;</hi> and Preſented it to the then At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney General, but was not allowed: Whereupon no Inquiſition, <hi>poſt mortem,</hi> was, or could be obtained, after the Deaths of the Two laſt Earls of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> viz. <hi>Algernoone,</hi> and <hi>Joſceline;</hi> which, if it might have been had, this Claymant, without doubt, or que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion, would have been found by the <hi>Jury,</hi> to have been the Couſin, and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſceline,</hi> the late Deceaſed-Earl of <hi>Northum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p n="8">8. Then the Claymant applyed himſelf to Sir <hi>Edward Walker,</hi> the KING's Herald at Arms; who was very Rough at firſt; but at laſt, was more Complyant; and did direct the Claymant in his Pedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree. And on the Day that the Pedigree was Finiſhed, the Clay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mant went to ſhew it him; and found him ſo ill, that he Died the next Day: And therefore, was prevented of his further Aſſiſtance.</p>
                        <p n="9">9. The Claymant's Sollicitor abuſed him, and cauſed ſeveral Lands to be beg'd by ſeveral Perſons, in the Name of the Duke of <hi>Monmouth,</hi> when he was in <hi>France:</hi> At his Return, the Claymant went to <hi>Windfor,</hi> to tender his Reſpects to him; and to prevent Dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferences, being loath to contend againſt a Perſon of his High Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity. And he moſt Graciouſly Complyed, and told the Complay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant; That he ſhould have a Fair Tryal at Law: And if the Clay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mant proved himſelf Heir-Male, God forbid, he ſhould hinder him. Upon which, the Plaintiff returned with great Joy; poſted away into <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and delivered Declarations in Ejectment, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on thoſe Lands the <hi>Duke</hi> had Recovered of the <hi>Counteſs,</hi> upon pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence there was no Heir-Male of the Family of the <hi>Percies</hi> Living. But when the Claymant was bringing the Tryal on, Priviledge was fet up: Whereupon, the Claymant went to Mr. <hi>Roſſe,</hi> the <hi>Duke</hi>'s Secretary, to know, why it was ſo, when the <hi>Duke</hi> did promiſe, He would not ſtand upon Priviledges; but a Fair Tryal ſhould be
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:47799:19"/>had? Mr. <hi>Roſſe</hi> Replyed, The <hi>Duke</hi> could not ſet aſide his Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge. To declare, how many Perſons, and how oft the Claymant hath been put off by Priviledges, would be too tedious for the Reader.</p>
                        <p n="10">10. When the Guardianſhip came to the <hi>Senior</hi> Counteſs <hi>Dowager</hi> the Claymant writ to her, and Craved her Anſwer; and ſent his Servant with the Letter, to <hi>Sion-Houſe:</hi> And her Anſwer was, That ſhe would not return any Anſwer in Writing. The Claymant writ alſo to the <hi>Junior</hi> Counteſs, and ſent Friends to Intercede. He likewiſe writ to Mr. <hi>Champion,</hi> and to Mr. <hi>Gee,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Clarke</hi> ſeveral times: And at one time, before the Tryal with Mr. <hi>Clarke,</hi> they would have owned the Plaintiff, to ſet him up; but broke off up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Terms: Although the Plaintiff was forced to ſuffer a Non-ſuit; yet that Tryal, and the Opinion of the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hales,</hi> convinced Sir <hi>Edward Walker,</hi> and the World. And this Clauſe is put in, meerly to ſatisfy the World; Becauſe ſome ſay, The Counteſs hath reported, what ſhe would do for an Heir-Male, of a true <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy.</hi> Others report, That the Claymant is ſo Stout, that he ſcorned to Apply himſelf to them. The Claymant hath Submitted beyond Reaſon, Law, and Equity; God himſelf is the Claymant's Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs: For, he hath ſet to his Seal a Creſſant; a Badge, which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs to the <hi>Percies</hi> Family, which he was Born into the World with; and is Deſcended of a Family, of near Thirty Generations: For <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Percy,</hi> was the Fifth Generation, and came in with <hi>William</hi> the <hi>Conqueror</hi> into <hi>England.</hi> And conſequently, the Clay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mant is by Matches, from <hi>Henry</hi> the Fourth <hi>Emperor,</hi> and of the Royal Blood of <hi>England,</hi> Legitimate by Father and Mother, Grand-Father and Grand-Mother, great Grand-Father and great Grand-Mother; as by the Oath of Mr. <hi>Henry Champion,</hi> in open Court: Whoſe great Grand-Father, Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> was the Third Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Fifth Earl of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p n="11">11. It is to be obſerved, That at that very Tryal, the Judgment and Verdict was Exemplified, under the Seal of his Majeſties Court of <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench:</hi> When the Plaintiff, <hi>James Percy,</hi> had proved his Father <hi>Henry Percy</hi> Marryed <hi>Lydia Cope,</hi> his Mother, at <hi>Horton</hi> in <hi>Northampton-ſhire;</hi> and that they had two Children, <hi>Henry</hi> and <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> both Elder than the Plaintiff. This did abate the Scandal of Baſtard and Impoſture: And my Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Rainsford,</hi> ſtood up, and ſaid; Gentlemen of the <hi>Jury,</hi> This is e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough to prove the Claymant Legitimate: We know his Pedigree, and that it muſt be heard before others. It is humbly ſuppos'd, he meant, before the KING's moſt Excellent Majeſty, and the Right Honorable, the LORDS and COMMONS Aſſembled in Parliament.</p>
                        <p>Therefore the Complaynant, after almoſt Nine years Proſecution of his Right, is forced, in order to ſatisfy all Impartial Readers, to preſent this his Caſe to the Publick View: If by any means (for the Honor of Juſtice, which Eſtabliſheth the Throne, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Free-born Subject in his Right) he may be Reſtored to the Place and Seat of his Anceſtors; there being many Preſidents in his own Family, that of the Earls of <hi>Kent,</hi> and others of the like Nature.</p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="pedigree">
                        <pb n="12" facs="tcp:47799:20"/>
                        <head>The <hi>PEDIGREE.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>
                           <hi>HEnry Percy,</hi> Firſt Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Created by King <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard</hi> the <hi>Second;</hi> Had Iſſue <hi>Henry,</hi> called <hi>Hotſpur:</hi> Both Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther and Son Attainted. Left Iſſue Male.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Grand-Son, was Reſtored by King <hi>Henry</hi> the <hi>Fifth;</hi> and made the Second Earl of <hi>Northumberland.</hi> Left Iſſue-Male.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Third Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> taking Part with King <hi>Henry</hi> the Sixth, was Slain. Left Iſſue-Male.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Fourth Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> after the Surrender of <hi>John Nevel,</hi> Lord Mountague, was Reſtored; and was Slain, in Performing his Duty for King <hi>Henry</hi> the Seventh. Left Iſſue-Male.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Fifth Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> left Iſſue Three Sons, <hi>viz.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <list>
                           <item>1. <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> 6 Earl, Dyed without Iſſue.</item>
                           <item>2. Sir <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> 2. Son, was Attaint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and Executed, in his Brother's Life<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time. Left Iſſue-Males.
<list>
                                 <item>Sir <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> Firſt Son, Created Seventh Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> by Queen <hi>Mary,</hi> after <hi>John</hi> Duke of <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland</hi> was Beheaded: And left no Iſſue-Male.</item>
                                 <item>Sir <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Second Son of Sir <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> that was Attainted, as above-ſaid, in King <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth's Time, and was the Eighth Earl of <hi>Northamberland,</hi> and left Iſſue-Males. [Note, the Miſtake:] Sir <hi>Richard Percy</hi> was this <hi>Henry Percy</hi>'s Son. So that, Sir <hi>Richard</hi> is found too Young by the Great Pedigree, to be the Clavmant's great Grand-Father.
<list>
                                       <item>
                                          <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> 9 Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> left Iſſue-Male.
<list>
                                             <item>
                                                <hi>Algernoon Percy,</hi> 10 Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> left Iſſue-Male.
<list>
                                                   <item>
                                                      <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> 11 Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Dyed, and left no Iſſue-Male.</item>
                                                </list>
                                             </item>
                                          </list>
                                       </item>
                                    </list>
                                 </item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                           <item>3. Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> Third Son, left Iſſue-Males.
<list>
                                 <item>
                                    <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Eldeſt Son &amp; Heir, left Iſſue-Males.
<list>
                                       <item>
                                          <hi>James Percy,</hi> Firſt Son, Dyed without Iſſue-Male.</item>
                                       <item>
                                          <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Second Son, left Iſſue-Males.
<list>
                                             <item>
                                                <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Firſt Son, dyed Young, left no Iſſue.</item>
                                             <item>
                                                <hi>James Percy,</hi> the now Claymant, ſecond Son, hath Three Sons.</item>
                                          </list>
                                       </item>
                                    </list>
                                 </item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                        <p>¶ <hi>It is to be obſerved, The</hi> Herald-Stainer <hi>in the Firſt Pedigree, did leave out Sir</hi> Ingleram; <hi>and likewiſe at another</hi> Herald-Stainers, <hi>where the Claymant found out the beſt In elligence: There he found that Leaf wanting of the Marriages of the</hi> Percies, <hi>which the Alphabet Directed unto; which much obſtructed the Claymant</hi>'s <hi>Endtavours.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>More-over, It is ſaid in Printed Books; That</hi> Thomas <hi>Rebell'd about the firſt Difference in Religion: But judicious Men judge, it was the Profuſeneſs of his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, in endeavouring to give away that, which in Law and Equity he ought not to do: Doubtleſs, this did Aggravate. And upon this Conſideration, was the Lands given back to the Sons. And if the Iſſue of a Rebellious Son be Reſtored, great Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon the Innocent ſhould Enjoy his Birth-Right.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>And whereas there are divers Lands annexed to the Title, and ſetled upon the Heirs-Males of the</hi> Percies <hi>for ever; which Lands are wrongfully Poſſeſt by the Females: And that by the Fraudulent Practice of his Sollicitor, other Lands are Beg'd, Bought, Sold, and Exchang'd: So that, no Deciſion can be had by Law. Therefore humbly prayes, As he is yet a Commoner, and a Free-born Subject of</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, <hi>that he may be Relieved by Act of Parliament, as is uſual in ſuch Caſes.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>By doing Juſtice in this your Day, may prevent the like Troubles from falling upon ſome of yours another Day.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>He humbly remains a Faithful Servant to God, to the King, &amp; to his Country.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>For the want of the Court of</hi> Wards, <hi>and the Court of</hi> Honors, <hi>forced the Claymant to Publiſh theſe Complaints.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>James Percy.</signed>
                        </closer>
                        <gap reason="missing" extent="2 pages">
                           <desc>〈2 pages missing〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:47799:20"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="account">
                        <head>This Following Account, I hope, will ſatisfy You, and the whole World.</head>
                        <opener>
                           <salute>Worthy Sir,</salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>Conſull <hi>Tooker</hi> informes me, that you declare, that if you were ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfied in my Pedigree, you would uſe your uttermoſt endeavour for Juſtice and Truth: Sir, When I Lodged at Doctor <hi>Chamber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lines,</hi> you came to me, and informed me of <hi>William Percy;</hi> I then took two Witneſſes, and went to him, and ſaid, Cozen, <hi>I know my ſelf to be next if Kin to Earl</hi> Percy <hi>that is dead, but cannot make out my great Grand-Father; I pray tell me, whom do you Claim under.</hi> He ſaid, <hi>My Fathers name was</hi> Henry Percy, <hi>and my Mothers Name was</hi> Mary Varnun, <hi>that lived with Madam</hi> Cope <hi>in</hi> Northampton-<hi>Shire.</hi> James <hi>replyed, My Fathers name was</hi> Henry Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy, <hi>and my Mothers name was</hi> Lydia Cope, <hi>and Dame</hi> Cope <hi>her Mother, was my Grand-Mother:</hi> William <hi>replyed, Certainly you are my brother; for I was told I had a brother living, but where he lived, and what became of him, I never heard till now. Col.</hi> William Ayrs <hi>ſaid, What</hi> Henry Percy <hi>was your Father? and whoſe brother was he?</hi> William <hi>replyed, he was the Earls brother, as the Agents told him; for he knew nothing but what they told him?</hi> James Percy <hi>replyed; but my Fathers Elder bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers name was</hi> James Percy, <hi>and was my God-Father, and he never had but one Daughter: and</hi> James <hi>my Uncle, and</hi> Henry <hi>my Father were the Sons of</hi> Henry Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy <hi>of</hi> Pavenham <hi>in</hi> Bedfordſhire, <hi>and my Grand-Father was ſent out of the North in</hi> Hampiers <hi>to old Madam</hi> Vaux <hi>in</hi> Northampton-ſhire, <hi>when the</hi> Percies <hi>were in trouble in Queen</hi> Elizabeth <hi>dayes, and it is my Grand-Fathers Father I cannot find, which would fix the Pedigree:</hi> Inſomuch, as the Counſels were at a ſtand; but was of Opinion, that by fixing on a wrong Perſon, was the only way to find out the Right. Note, that the aforegoing is enough to ſatisfie a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny reaſonable man, that <hi>James Percy</hi> and <hi>William Percy</hi> muſt be brothers; for <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy</hi> was never Married. Now <hi>Henry</hi> the Father of this <hi>James</hi> was Married to <hi>Lydia Cope</hi> in the year 1614, as by the Regiſter Book, and this True Claymant <hi>James Percy</hi> was born 1619. And there was <hi>Henry</hi> and <hi>Eli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zabeth,</hi> both elder than <hi>James;</hi> then what ſignifies <hi>William</hi> the Son of <hi>Mary Var<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nun,</hi> who was born in the Year 1627: which proves him an Aprentiſhip Younger; but if he proves his Mother Married to our Father, then he ought to go by the Name of <hi>William Percy;</hi> and if not Married, then to go by the Name of <hi>William Varnun.</hi> I ſhould never have uncovered my Fathers Naked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, had not my brother (and wicked Agents, and men hard of belief) for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced me to it; therefore mark well the following practices.</p>
                        <p n="1">1. When <hi>James Percy</hi> the Claymant was at a loſs, and could not find his great Grand-Father, then the Agents put <hi>William Percy</hi> to Claim under <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy, Algernoon</hi> the Tenth Earls brother.</p>
                        <p n="2">2. When <hi>James</hi> Claimed under Sir <hi>Richard Percy,</hi> then they put out a Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digree, pretending to undeceive the people; and there my younger brother is pretended to deſcend from <hi>William Percy</hi> the elder brother of Sir <hi>Richard Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy;</hi> ſo cunningly placing of the Younger brother, before the Elder, the more to wildernize the elder brother, and amuſe the World.</p>
                        <p n="3">3. When the Tryal was to be had againſt <hi>Clark,</hi> then they would have owned the Claimant <hi>James Percy,</hi> and ſet him up in all haſt; as the Book relates more at large, at the Tryal before Judge <hi>Hales.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p n="4">4. Further; to keep the Elder brother <hi>James Percy</hi> in darkneſs, the Leaf in the Heralds book was rent out, concerning the Matches of the <hi>Percies.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p n="5">5. The Herald that drew the firſt Pedigree left Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy</hi> out; yet by Judge <hi>Hales</hi> direction, and Sir <hi>Edward Walkers,</hi> and the help of Friends, the Truth was found out at laſt according to the Counſels direction; notwithſtanding their ſetting him forth in the <hi>Gazzets</hi> to be an Impoſter.</p>
                        <p n="6">6. When he firſt went into the North, to deliver declarations in Ejectments, <hi>James Percy</hi> the Claymant, was poiſoned at <hi>New-Gaſtle;</hi> &amp;, at <hi>York,</hi> was arreſted on two ſeveral Actions of 20000l. each Action: &amp; for the bits &amp; half Tryals, I have
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:47799:21"/>at vaſt Charges and pains obtained, I refer you to the Book, wherein is not a Tyth of the Complaints and Wrongs done and Committed by the Agents.</p>
                        <p n="7">7. Remember how <hi>Clark</hi> dyed in the North, and how Mr. <hi>Champion</hi> dyed in the South, who did to his power blindfold the Truth; Note alſo, after <hi>Clark</hi>'s Tryal, I went to Mr. <hi>Champions</hi> houſe at <hi>Thiſtle-worth,</hi> and told him, That God would re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venge my innocent Cauſe; for certainly there would a Curſe attend ſuch horrid practices ſo unjuſtly continued againſt the True Heir that was owned by Judges and Juries: and all wiſe men that underſtand what they read, may eaſily diſcern Truth from Falſhood: &amp; to that end doubtleſs, the great God hath ſet to his Seal, the Half Moon, (a badge belonging to the <hi>Percys</hi>) a Creſcent or Mole upon the True brother, and Heir of the <hi>Percies.</hi> Now if men will be of ſuch hard belief, God will ſhew Wonders, before Truth ſhall be Overthrown and Trampled under Foot. This acount, I hope, will confirm your Judgement, and cauſe you to imbrace the Truth.</p>
                        <div type="part">
                           <head>Take theſe further Arguments and Reaſons.</head>
                           <p>MR. <hi>Henry Champion</hi> ownes, that <hi>Henry Percy</hi> that lived with my Lord <hi>Bacon,</hi> was the right Heir, had he lived; and that <hi>William</hi> was his Son: So Mr. <hi>Buſhell</hi> and Mr. <hi>Fleetwood</hi> would often tell me, the Claymant <hi>James Percy,</hi> that they were fellow-ſervants with my Father, <hi>Henry Percy;</hi> and have often heard <hi>Joſcelin Percy,</hi> and the reſt of thoſe Eight brethren, call <hi>Henry</hi> the Father of <hi>James</hi> Cozen, and were wondrous familier when they met at my Lord <hi>Bacons;</hi> Had that Lord continued in proſperity, <hi>Henry Percy</hi> his ſervant, had not known ſo much miſery, nor <hi>James Percy</hi> (<hi>Henry</hi>'s Son) had not run through the Gantlets of extre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mities. Mr. <hi>Champion</hi> could have done Juſtice at that meeting at Doctor <hi>Lamplues,</hi> if he had pleaſed; but he rather takes advantage at the Claymants weakneſs. We ſhall ſay no more of him, but he that blowes out his Neighbors Candle willfully, may want light juſtly, before he dies.</p>
                           <p>Furthermore, it is well known, that <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> the Father of <hi>James</hi> and <hi>William,</hi> took his wife <hi>Lydia,</hi> and her Children, and carryed them to <hi>Dunington</hi> in <hi>Lincoln<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhire,</hi> and there left them; and then took <hi>Mary Varnun</hi> (the Servant of Dame <hi>Cope</hi>) and carry's her to <hi>London;</hi> at which old <hi>Henry</hi> the Nineth Earl was Angry; if things had been right, he would have ſcorned to have ſeen <hi>William</hi> to have been brought up by the Pariſh. Had Juſtice <hi>Scroggs</hi> ſuffered the Witneſſes, to ſpeak at the Tryal, it would have been ſufficiently prov'd, that <hi>James Percy</hi> and <hi>Henry Percy</hi> were brothers; and the Son's of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> that was ſent out of the North in Hampiers, and was ſo owned by <hi>Henry</hi> the Nine Earl, and his ſeven brethren, and did oft viſit each other.</p>
                           <p>Furthermore, <hi>Algernoon</hi> the Tenth Earl, did own <hi>James,</hi> the Unkle in <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> to be the next Heir, if his Brother <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy,</hi> died without Iſſue Male of his Body, [<hi>Note,</hi> Joſceline <hi>was not then Born</hi>] and ſent <hi>James Percy,</hi> the Unckle of <hi>James</hi> the Claymant, 100 <hi>l.</hi> into <hi>Ireland;</hi> and likewiſe, did often own <hi>James Percy,</hi> the Trunckmaker; and give him money, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledged, That he was the next Heir-male, if his Son ſhould dye, and leave no Heire-males of his Body.</p>
                           <p>Moreover, <hi>Henry</hi> Lord <hi>Percy</hi> (brother to <hi>Algernoon</hi>) the tenth Earl, did de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare on his Death-bed, that <hi>James Percy</hi> a Trunckmaker, was the next Heir, if his Brothers Son ſhould die.</p>
                           <p>And alſo <hi>Joſcelin</hi> the eleventh Earl beyond Sea, did declare, upon his death<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bed, That <hi>James Percy</hi> the Trunck-maker in <hi>Ireland,</hi> was the next Heir-Male, if he were living; and Cryed out, <hi>Oh that he were here now.</hi> And as for <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Percy,</hi> alias <hi>Varnun,</hi> he was never owned by any, but Mr. <hi>Champion,</hi> who en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour'd to act the part of <hi>Jacobs</hi> Mother; Had <hi>Henry Percy</hi> (the Father of <hi>James</hi> the Claymant) lived in theſe times, he needed not to have Fled for his Crime: Could <hi>James Percy</hi> have had a fair Tryal, he would have printed no more.</p>
                           <p>But, when you came firſt to me, I ſhewed you a <hi>Mold</hi> like a <hi>half-Moon</hi> upon my Body, (born into the World with it) as hath been the like on ſome of the <hi>Percy</hi>'s formerly; now, ſearch <hi>William Percy,</hi> and ſee if God hath marked him ſo;
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:47799:21"/>ſurely, God did foreſee the troubles, although the Law takes no notice: But God makes a true deciſion, even as he was pleaſed, to make <hi>Eſau</hi> hairy, and <hi>Jacob</hi> ſmooth; if I (like old Father <hi>Iſaack</hi>) could not See (through the miſt of Igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance, and miſguidements of Politicians) the right road of my Pedigree; yet now by Providence, I can (like old <hi>Tobias</hi>) ſee perfectly the <hi>Rebeccaical</hi> Actions, that hath been practis'd againſt me, and how they endeavour to ſteal away my Birth-right, and my Bleſſing too.</p>
                           <p>And ſince it is your deſire, to be ſatisfi'd, be pleas'd patiently to hear a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of my Solicitors Treacherous Practiſes, as Mr. <hi>Champion</hi> was pleas'd to ſay to me in the Temple-Walks: Mr. <hi>Percy, who helpt you to your Solicitor?</hi> I repli'd; <hi>I believe your ſelf, or the Devil ſent him to me.</hi>
                           </p>
                           <p>This Solicitor Mr. <hi>Tho. Swayne,</hi> perſwades me into Articles; then carryes me down to <hi>Pimborne</hi> in <hi>Dorſet-ſhire,</hi> to his own Houſe, pretending to carry me to old Mr. <hi>Roger's</hi> of <hi>Canington</hi> in <hi>Somerſet</hi>-ſhire; ſaying, <hi>He did not doubt, but upon reaſonable termes, to prevail with the old man, to put me in poſſeſſion of the Eſtate, in his life time.</hi> But when he had put me to ſo vaſt Charges, then he pretended, he might get his Brains beat out; for he was informed, he was an Old Croſs Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, and therefore he would not go. The next Project he had, was, That I had great Perſons to deal withal; and I muſt get Courtiers that were in the Kings Favour, and he was well acquainted with them; but he would apply himſelf firſt, to the Lord <hi>Newport,</hi> and propound a Match for one of his Daughters, to my Eldeſt Son; but inſtead of the Match, the Lord <hi>Newport</hi> had begg'd the Lands, for the Duke of <hi>Monmouth;</hi> when in truth, the Duke was in <hi>France;</hi> and <hi>Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nington</hi> Lands was begg'd by other Courtiers, by the Contrivance of the Soli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>citor; unknown, and altogether againſt the Opinion or Conſent of <hi>James Percy,</hi> the Claimant; and when the Solicitor ſaw the Clyant ſo enraged; ſaith he, <hi>The Lord of</hi> Newport <hi>can do what he pleaſes with the Duke of</hi> Monmouth; <hi>ſo that the Duke upon the Match, ſhould return the Lands again.</hi> But when <hi>Percy</hi> would not be ſatisfyed, then <hi>Swayne</hi> would meet with him at my Lord <hi>Newport</hi>'s Lodgings, at <hi>Whitehal: Percy</hi> met at the Hour appointed, (<hi>Swayne</hi> being then with the Lord); but <hi>Percy</hi> was denyed. The next day, <hi>Swayne</hi> gave <hi>Percy</hi> a Letter to the Lord, to ſatisfy himſelf. The Lord anſwered him, <hi>Mr.</hi> Percy, <hi>You muſt believe your Solicitor.</hi> But being earneſt with my Lord, he replyed; <hi>Mr.</hi> Percy, <hi>If you will truſt to me, I will be your Faithful Friend: But the Truth is, I dare not appear publickly for you, I am ſo near related to that Family.</hi> Whereupon <hi>Percy</hi> replyed; <hi>Nay, my Lord, if you dare not appear publickly for me, I dare not truſt you privatly:</hi> So pray'd <hi>God</hi> to Bleſs him, and took Leave to depart.</p>
                           <p>Then <hi>Swayne</hi> the Solicitor, contrived three Suits at Law, againſt <hi>Percy</hi> his Cly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ant, which laſted Three Years; and <hi>Percy</hi> caſt <hi>Swayne</hi> in all the three Actions, but could not catch him for his Coſts.</p>
                           <p>And now the Duke of <hi>Monmouth</hi> hath Sold thoſe Lands that was beg'd, and was worth Nine or Ten Thouſand Pound <hi>per annum,</hi> for Twelve Thouſand Pound: But Six Thouſand for the Duke's part; and the Lord <hi>Newport,</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, had the Remainder; as the Claymant is informed.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Note,</hi> In that Act of <hi>Parliament,</hi> which <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Sixth Earl, was ſo pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe, in Letting long Leaſes to his Servants, Tenants, and others; and Exchang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing thoſe Lands, which of right he ought not to do: Yet there was many Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vings in that Act, which was ſettled upon the Heir-Males of the <hi>Percies</hi> for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver; which would not be ſuffered to be read at the Tryals. But Learned Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſels were of opinion, That his ſettling the Lands in the Crown, was to ingra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiate himſelf in the <hi>King</hi>'s Favour; queſtioning not, but that the <hi>King</hi> would Reſtore all the Lands again to the Sons of <hi>Thomas</hi> that Rebell'd, and was Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted in the Life-time of his Brethren: And his Sons was a Bar to Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> the Younger Brother; or elſe, Sir <hi>Ingleram,</hi> without all doubt, had been immediately Seized of the Eſtate, after the Earl, his Elder Brother's Death: For <hi>Thomas</hi> his Attaint, did not prejudice the Elder Brother, nor hurt the Younger Brother; He only Corrupted his own Line. Now, Mr. <hi>Clark,</hi> Mr. <hi>Champion,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Gee,</hi> did make uſe of their time; and by Favour, poſſeſt themſelves of moſt s
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:47799:22"/>of thoſe Lands, as the ſeveral Leaſes and Lives were expired: And to continue thoſe Lands, in policy they ſet up <hi>William Percy;</hi> thinking they might pleaſe him, as they do Children with an Apple.</p>
                           <p>Had the Agents ſent me Money, ſo often as they did <hi>William,</hi> they had done well; but oppoſing me (the True Heir) againſt their own Knowledge, they have done very unjuſtly: For Mr. <hi>Orlando Gee</hi> well knows, I made my Claim at <hi>Petmouth,</hi> in the Year 1654.</p>
                        </div>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>I am your Cordial Friend. J. P.</signed>
                        </closer>
                        <postscript>
                           <opener>
                              <salute>SIR,</salute>
                           </opener>
                           <p>I Have, according to my Promiſe, given you a true Account; as I did at firſt, when I was igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant, and could not make out my Great Grand-Father, to fix my Pedigree. But when Mr. <hi>Henry Champion,</hi> at Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi>'s Tryal, was forced upon his Oath; then he confeſt, that Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy</hi> (who was hid from me before) was Marryed, and had Sons and Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters. Mr. <hi>Champion</hi> knew this, when the Letters and Mony was ſent to my Brother <hi>William.</hi> I wonder, a Wife Man as you are, ſhould be ſo deceived by him: And the World may wonder at me, that have trac'd their Treacheries, and diſſembling Actions; and found them out ſo, as it will continue to their ſhame, another Day. Had the Agents been true to themſelves, they ſhould have acted the Honeſt Part; as Mr. <hi>Champion</hi> was once about to do, at my firſt Coming over. For, he came to me, and ſaid; <hi>Mr.</hi> Percy, <hi>Will you own the Old Servants?</hi> I replyed, <hi>Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording as they ſhall deſerve.</hi> And then Mr. <hi>Gee</hi> came to me, and ſaid; <hi>Was you the Man, that came to</hi> Petworth, <hi>in the Year</hi> 54? And with the Circumſtantial Remembrances I gave, ſilenced him. Truly, I am aſhamed to declare their unworthy Actions, and what they have forced me to. Now, ſuppoſe they had proved <hi>Mary Varnon</hi> Marryed; yet I was ſeven Years elder. But to put up a poor indigent Man, a Journy-man-Glover, &amp; Chriſtening his Children, to deceive the World; and to ſlight the true Heir, becauſe I was a Trunck-maker: The Trade is Good; and by <hi>God</hi>'s Bleſſing, it hath given me Bread in the Extremity of my Travels, till I obtained the Merchandizing Trade: And can make my Three Sons Free-Men, &amp; Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> and <hi>Dublin</hi> in <hi>Ireland,</hi> and of <hi>Norwich</hi> in <hi>Norfolk;</hi> and have likewiſe Trayned them up to Handycrafts: So that, if they fail in the Myſtery of Merchandizing, they may (with <hi>God</hi>'s Bleſſing) Live upon their Ingenuity.</p>
                           <p>Yet, one word more, in my Father, <hi>Henry Percy</hi>'s behalf, by way of Compariſon. There was one of the Female Sex, that was addicted to Venery; and a Perſon of Quality, being over ſeen, had to do with her; and ſhe laid the Child to him, though ſome other might have got it: And ſuch People are not much to be blamed, for getting the beſt Father they can, for the Child.</p>
                           <p>To conclude: I muſt not forget to tell you, what the Agents are doing now amongſt the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants, as I am informed: They call all their Courts for the Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> by the Name of <hi>Percy;</hi> and informs all the Tenants, That <hi>James Percy</hi> (the Ten Years Claymant) is Run away: But by <hi>God</hi>'s Providence, I remain at Mr. <hi>Ralph Carter</hi>'s Houſe, a Trunck-maker in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet,</hi> over againſt <hi>Serjeant</hi>'s-<hi>Inn:</hi> where the Meſſenger may find <hi>James Percy,</hi> to Serve the <hi>King</hi>'s Royal Writ of Summons upon.</p>
                           <p>Since I ſaw you, I preſented a Petition into the <hi>King</hi>'s ſacred Hand: And His gracious An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer to the Maſter of Requeſt, was, as at the Beginning, when I firſt Petitioned the <hi>King;</hi> whom <hi>God</hi> Bleſs with long Life here, and Eternal Happineſs hereafter. You will find the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tition and Anſwer, in the Firſt Sheet added to this Book. If a Tinker was taken in his Travels, a Laborer from under his Hod of Morter, and a Sawyer out of the Saw-Pit, to Enjoy their Birth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right and Inheritance; then, Why may not <hi>James Percy,</hi> the true Heir to the Earldom of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> be call'd from a Trunck-makers Houſe, to take his Place and Seat, in the Right Honourable Houſe of PEERS; according to his Birth-right and Title.</p>
                           <p>YOu was pleaſed to tell me, That Diſguſt was taken againſt me, for the Verſes I ſent to the <hi>Counteſs.</hi> I muſt confeſs, I writ them in a great Paſſion; becauſe the <hi>Counteſs</hi> would not vouchſafe to ſpeak with me, but peept through the Window at me. And becauſe I begun with a Verſe, I will end with a Verſe; by reaſon the <hi>Counteſs</hi> ſhall ſee, I am ſtill the ſame Man: And ſo, leave the Cauſe to <hi>GOD,</hi> to the <hi>KING, Parliament,</hi> and <hi>People,</hi> to Judg, whether Pought to loſe my Birth-right, for ſo ſmall an Offence, as theſe following Verſes.</p>
                           <lg>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Wealth is the</hi> Gyant <hi>grown ſo high,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>That can a</hi> Percy <hi>now defye:</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Though, like</hi> David, <hi>with Sling and Stones,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Shews Great Champion's Blood and Bones.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>Saul <hi>ſeeking Aſſes, Kingdom mes;</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>James <hi>ſeeks his Right, finds Foes too Great.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Pray</hi> God <hi>give me a Zealous Heart,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>That I may ſeek the Better Part:</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Then ſhall I Sing his Praiſes clear;</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Scorn to peep through a Window here.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>This is done, that it ſhall be ſaid,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>A</hi> Percy <hi>Lives, though</hi> Joſceline's <hi>Dead,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Reſolv'd I am, to ſpend my All,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Before a</hi> Percy's <hi>Name ſhall Fall.</hi>
                              </l>
                           </lg>
                           <p>If the afore ſaid Verſes gave Offence, I hope theſe following Verſes will not.</p>
                           <lg>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>An</hi> Impoſtor <hi>is a Baſe Name;</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>By doing Juſtice, clears the Shame:</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>And blows away the Clouds ſo high;</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>Makes Truth ſhine clear, as</hi> Sun <hi>in Sky.</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>I truſt in</hi> God, <hi>that can Reſtore,</hi>
                              </l>
                              <l>
                                 <hi>If not on Earth, to Heavens Shore.</hi>
                              </l>
                           </lg>
                           <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
                        </postscript>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:22"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:23"/>
               <pb n="1" facs="tcp:47799:23" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>THE CASE OF JAMES PERCY, The true Heir-Male and Claimant to the <hi>Earldom of Northumberland,</hi>
                        </head>
                        <head type="sub">To the Honourable <hi>Knights, Citizens,</hi> and <hi>Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſſes;</hi> And to the <hi>Committee</hi> of <hi>Grievances,</hi> in PARLIAMENT Aſſembled.</head>
                        <head type="sub">The Humble Petition of <hi>JAMES PERCY,</hi> Cozen and next Heir-Male to <hi>JOSCELIN PERCY,</hi> the late and Eleventh <hi>EARL</hi> of <hi>NORTHUMBERLAND,</hi> Deceaſed.</head>
                        <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                        <p>THAT your Petitioner was the Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> who was the Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> who was the Son of Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> who was the third Son of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> Fifth Earl of <hi>Northumberland:</hi> By which Deſcent your Petitioner is Entitled to the <hi>Earldom of Northumber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and to ſeveral <hi>Baronies, Honours, Manors</hi> and <hi>Lands,</hi> which to the <hi>Earl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom</hi> and <hi>Baronies</hi> have been and ſtill are annexed; your Petitioner having proved his Pedigree, queſtions not but by your Aſſiſtance to make appear they are, or ſhould be his Right, and Juſt Inheritance, as Cozen and Heir-Male to <hi>Joſcelin</hi> late Earl afore-mentioned: And therefore ought to fit in <hi>Parliament,</hi> and enjoy the Place, Seat and Preheminence of his Anceſtors, with the Dignities to him ſo deſcended, and do of Right belong: And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore prays his Bill may be be made an Act to ſettle the Title and Eſtate toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther again, that Property and Right may be had according to Juſtice.</p>
                        <p>That at his firſt coming to Claim, your Petitioner petitioned the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty, who was graciouſly pleaſed to ſay, <hi>God forbid We ſhould hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der an Heir, but that he ſhould have the benefit of the Law.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>That your Petitioner applyed himſelf to the Lords in Parliament, where he then could not prove his Great Grandfather, which forc'd his Councel to tell
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:47799:24"/>their Lordſhips, That the Claimants Cauſe lay not before them, but ought to be Tryed at the Common Law firſt; and when the Cauſe had went through the Inferiour Courts to prove his Pedigree, and if the Law could not end it, then the Cauſe ought to come before their Lordſhips again, to Hear, Debate, and to Determine. And at that time his potent Adverſaries did publiſh in the <hi>Gazette,</hi> that your Petitioner was an Impoſtor; and at their Courts did de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare to all the Tenants, that the Claimants name was not <hi>Percy,</hi> but that he was a <hi>Baſtard;</hi> and that <hi>Henry Percy</hi> whom he declared was his Father, they could prove was never Married: Yet they have made all the Waſte imaginable, cutting down Woods, pulling down Caſtles, over-working of Lead-Mines and Coal-Mines; and not only ſo, but it caſt the Petitioner out of Favour in the World, that His moſt Excellent Majeſty was pleaſed to give the Title one way, and the Land ſeveral ways; which hath not only multiplied Enemies, but by their Power, Policy and Priviledge, hath put off your Petitioner near Eleven Years.</p>
                        <p>Therefore your Petitioner renders this following Account, that his Juſt Cauſe may be known, what hard uſage he hath found at Law. That the firſt Tryal was in the year 1674. againſt Mr. <hi>John Clerke,</hi> the chief Agent, for ſcan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dalous words, who ſhelter'd under Priviledge a long time; and before the Tryal, they offer'd to Own him, and to aſſiſt the Claimant <hi>James Percy</hi> with their Books, Pedigree and Records, but would not be bound to perform: Then the Plaintiff perceived it to be a baffle for a longer delay, and there were no good Faith in them; then ſaid the Plaintiff, <hi>Currat Lex,</hi> I will have the Tryal if it be but to waſh the dirt off, which the <hi>Gazette</hi> and your evil practices have thrown upon me: And at the Tryal, the Attorney would ſuffer a Non-ſuit, without the conſent of his Client; at which the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hales</hi> ſeemed not to be ſatisfied, but ſtood up and ſaid, That <hi>James Percy</hi> the Claimant and Plaintiff, had proved himſelf a true <hi>Percy,</hi> legitimate by Father and Mother, Grandfather and Grandmother, and of the Bloud and Family of the <hi>Percies</hi> of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> and did verily believe, that the Plaintiff was Cozen and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſcelin</hi> the late and 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Earl of <hi>Northumber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> only he was afraid he had taken his Deſcent a little too low: And the Jury at a Treat which Mr. <hi>Clerke</hi> the Defendant gave them, ſaid to Mr. <hi>Clerke,</hi> You are beholden to Mr. <hi>Percy</hi> for ſuffering a Non-ſuit, for truly we muſt have given a Verdict for the Plaintiff, his Cauſe was proved ſo clear: and the Damages was laid in the Declaration 10000 <hi>l.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>The ſecond Tryal was upon an Ejectment for <hi>Cunnington</hi> and <hi>Rodoway</hi> Lands in <hi>Somerſetſhire,</hi> which Lands of right fell to the Heirs-Males of the <hi>Percies,</hi> after the Heirs-Males of the <hi>Rogers</hi> was extinct: Doubtleſs it was by miſ-information his Majeſty was miſtaken in his Gifts: And at that Tryal the Pedigree was fully proved up to the Plaintiffs Great-Grandfather Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy,</hi> youngeſt Son of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> 5<hi rend="sup">th.</hi> Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> by the Oath of Mr. <hi>Henry Champion,</hi> who was Steward to the Earls of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and declared at that Tryal, that he found in the Books and Records of the <hi>Percies,</hi> that Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy</hi> was married, and had Sons and Daughters: ſo that a Verdict ought to have been had for the Plaintiffs Pedigree at that Tryal alſo. And Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi> did not only ſhelter under Priviledge, but when the Writs of Error were put into the Houſe of Lords, he then ſued the Plaintiff
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:47799:24"/>in the Court of Kings-Bench, and got Coſt, and broke the Priviledge of Parliament.</p>
                        <p>The third Tryal was againſt one Mr. <hi>Wright,</hi> for the like ſcandalous words, where your Petitioner proved his Legitimacy again, and not the Tythe of his Witneſſes were examined; for the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Rainsford</hi> ſtood up and ſaid, Gentlemen of the Jury, we need not trouble the Court to examine more of the Plaintiffs Witneſſes, by reaſon his Pedigree was fully proved before, at a former Tryal at the Bar of this Court: And when the Jury brought in but 300 <hi>l.</hi> Damages, the Lord Chief Juſtice was angry, and told them they had undervalued the Plaintiffs Cauſe; (the Judgment exemplified under the Seal of the Court, makes appear the ſame.)</p>
                        <p>That the fourth Tryal againſt <hi>John Blakeston</hi> 
                           <abbr>Eſq</abbr> who was likewiſe an Agent for the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> and kept her Courts, and did declare the like ſcandalous words, and gave it in all his Charges to the Jury and Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants, to take ſpecial notice thereof: And at the Tryal on <hi>Monday</hi> the 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of <hi>November</hi> 1678. the words were proved. The Declaration was allowed, after ſome debate upon a nice word, which was amended: But the Councel for the Defendant ſtarted up an Attainder in the Caſe, which the Plaintiffs Councel was not prepared at that time to remove that. Objection, but the Tryal was put by at that time, and the Jury was withdrawn, as the Plaintiffs printed Book declares more at large. But the ſecond part of that Tryal was upon the 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of <hi>February</hi> 1678. a new Jury upon the motion of the Defendants Councel did appear, and the Plaintiffs Councel did clear that point concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Attainder, by reaſon the Plaintiffs Councel made appear to the Court, that <hi>James Percy</hi> was deſcended from the Body of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> 5<hi rend="sup">th.</hi> Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> of Sir <hi>Ingleram Percy</hi> his youngeſt Son, and that the Colla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teral Line was never Attainted; and therefore ought to enjoy the Title and Eſtate of his Anceſtors Earls of <hi>Northumberland.</hi> Then the Defendants Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cel and the Court did own the Plaintiffs Title and Pedigree, but ſaid there was no Lands to ſupport the Title: then the Plaintiff prayed, that the Court would confirm what they owned by a Rule in Court; whereupon the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Scrogs</hi> ſtood up and ſaid, Confirm or not confirm, the Declaration is naught, diſcharge <hi>Blakeſton</hi> from the Suit of <hi>Percy;</hi> notwithſtanding the vaſt Charge the Plaintiff had been put to, by the Defendants ſheltering under the <hi>ſenior</hi> Counteſs of <hi>Northumberlands</hi> Priviledges: And when the Duke of <hi>Monmouth</hi> had ſet aſide her Priviledges, then he ſhelter'd himſelf under the Lord of <hi>Eſſex</hi> his Priviledge: And when the Plaintiff had made his complaint to the Houſe of Lords, the Lord of <hi>Eſſex</hi> did agree with the Plaintiffs Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cel, that if Mr. <hi>Clerk</hi>'s Coſt was laid down in Court for his ſecurity, the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant Mr. <hi>Blakeston</hi> ſhould not ſtand upon Priviledge, but go on to Tryal: Then the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Scrogs</hi> ſtood up and ſaid, Mr. <hi>Percy,</hi> if you will lay down the 90 <hi>l.</hi> Mr. <hi>Clerk</hi>'s Coſt in Court, the Lord of <hi>Eſſex</hi> will not inſiſt upon Priviledge, and we do promiſe you ſhall have a fair Tryal: Whereupon the Money was tender'd accordingly, and the 90 <hi>l.</hi> was got out of Court be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he had notice by his Attorney Mr. <hi>Hancock,</hi> or before the Tryal was ended. And in truth the 90 <hi>l.</hi> the Opponents ought not to have had, by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon the 90 <hi>l.</hi> Coſt ought to have been ſet aſide upon their own Demurrer. Moreover it is to be noted, that Sir <hi>George Jeffreys</hi> was Councel for the
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:47799:25"/>Plaintiff at the fore part of the Tryal, and had taken 40 <hi>s.</hi> a Retaining Fee, and 3 <hi>l.</hi> a Pleading Fee, and had the Petitioner's Breviate; but at the latter part of his Tryal, pleaded againſt the Petitioner, notwithſtanding the Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff tender'd him new Fees, and complained of him in Court. All which cauſed the Plaintiff to Appeal to the Parliament by two Writs of Error, to have the Errors argued, and his Title to be brought to an Iſſue, to be call'd to the Place and Seat of his Anceſtors, according to his Birthright.</p>
                        <p>That the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty hath been graciouſly pleaſed to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferr your Petitioner to the Lords in Parliament, to hear and determine his ſaid Cauſe; and to that purpoſe, he hath been at vaſt Charges in renewing his two Writs of Error, after every Prorogation; and his Attorney hath re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived 60 <hi>l.</hi> only for the Kings Hand, beſides all other Charges which far ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeded. And his ſaid Attorney did promiſe your Petitioner, to get all his Breviates in a readineſs againſt the Tryal, but did altogether fail, as the printed Petition hereunto annexed makes appear. Moreover he told your Petitioner ſometime before, that he could have had <hi>a hundred Goineys</hi> to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tray your Petitioner; and ſome other of your Petitioners Councel have been tempted with Bribes, but they were ſo Juſt as to refuſe.</p>
                        <p>And now the Agents have ſurprized your Petitioner, for they knew the Error muſt have been proved againſt the Plaintiff Mr. <hi>Blakeſton;</hi> ſo that they would not take their Coſt for that days diſappointment, according to the prayer of the printed Petition, but have obtained the Writ of Error to be diſmiſt the Lords Houſe, without any fair Hearing: ſo that all they have done, and do, is by way of ſurprizal, to tire the Claimant out of his juſt Right.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>He therefore moſt humbly beſeeches the Honourable Houſe of Commons, as he is yet but a Commoner, that for the Glory of God, the Honour of our King and Kingdom, to ſtand up for Justice, ſo that Property and Right may be preſerved, and the Oppreſſed may be relieved, for this is the</hi> 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. <hi>year of your Petitioners Claim: And intercede with the Kings moſt Excellent Majesty, and the Right Honourable Lords Spiritual and Temporal, not to ſuffer a Loyal Subject to be over-powered, but that his juſt Claim may be heard with patience, and determined in Juſtice; and that your Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioners Bill may be made an Act, to reſtore the true Heir to his Birth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right, and that the Title and the Estate that is now diſperſed into ſeveral hands, may be forthwith ſettled by an Act of Parliament.</hi> And he ſhall ever pray.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>Near 300 <hi>l.</hi> the two Writs of Error have coſt, for putting into Parliament, continuing and renewing after every Prorogation, and now they have Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion upon <hi>Blakeſton</hi>'s Writ of Error, before the Caſe is heard.</p>
            <p>The Attorney-General ſaid, Mr. <hi>Percy, Now you have no where to Appeal but to Heaven:</hi> But if Juſtice be not done on Earth, we may fear Gods Vengeance will come from Heaven: Therefore the Petitioner is forc'd to Appeal to thoſe Worthies in the Houſe of Commons for Juſtice, and therefore he hath annexed the printed Petitions.</p>
            <q>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:47799:25"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the KINGS moſt Excellent Majeſty; And to the Right Honourable Lords Spiritual and Temporal in PARLIAMENT Aſſembled. <hi>The Humble Petition of</hi> JAMES PERCY.</head>
                        <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                        <p>THat after your Petitioner's Complaint againſt his Attorneys, <hi>James Hooton, Edward Fyfield,</hi> and <hi>John Hancock;</hi> Mr. <hi>James Hooton,</hi> one of your Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioner's Attorneys, underſtanding the Complaints againſt him, ſent the Writings by his Man, which came too late; out of which Papers his Breviates ought to have been drawn, which doth teſtifie the Truth of your Petitioner's Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint, and what he offered to confirm upon Oath before your Lordſhips.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>Therefore your Petitioner moſt Humbly prays, That the two Writs of Error may be continued between</hi> Percy <hi>Plaintiff, and</hi> Blakeſton <hi>Defendant, and</hi> Utting <hi>Plaintiff, and</hi> Coppleſton <hi>Defendant; and that his Councel that he hath Retained formerly, may be allowed your Petitioner to argue the ſaid Cauſe: that is to ſay, Sir</hi> William Jones, <hi>Serjeant</hi> Pemberton, <hi>and Serjeant</hi> Simpſon, <hi>and that a new day may be ordered now his Witneſſes are in Town, and deſires no longer time then his Councel may well conſider: And further prays, That a moderate Coſts may be tax'd, upon account of the Attorneys Negligence.</hi> And your Petitioner ſhall ever pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>It is hoped, that the Neglect of the Attorneys ſhall not deſtroy a man's Birth-right, Title and Inheritance.</p>
            <p>Your Petitioner's Cauſe being before your Lordſhips to hear and determine, therefore humbly prays, that a new day may be Ordered, before his Witneſſes be diſperſed.</p>
            <q>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:47799:26"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the KINGS moſt Excellent Majeſty, in PARLIAMENT. <hi>The Humble Petition of</hi> JAMES PERCY.</head>
                        <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                        <p>THat this annexed Petition, fairly writ, was preſented at the Bar of the Lords Houſe the 10<hi rend="sup">th.</hi> Inſtant.</p>
                        <p>That your Petitioner is at a vaſt Charge in keeping his Witneſſes in Town, waiting for an Order, and a Day appointed, according to the prayer of the ſaid Petition.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>He therefore prays, That your Majeſty would be graciouſly pleaſed to call for the ſaid Petition, and cauſe it to be Read; and that a ſhort day may be appointed, that a fair Hearing may be had, to find out the Truth, and that Juſtice may be done accordingly: And let it not be ſaid in</hi> England, <hi>that the Innocent are puniſhed, and the Guilty go free: But call to mind how merciful God hath been, in Reſtrring your Majeſty; Even ſo in pity Reſtore your poor diſtreſſed Subject.</hi> And he ſhall ever pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>This Petition was preſented into his Majeſties Sacred Hand, the 15<hi rend="sup">th.</hi> of <hi>December</hi> 1680.</p>
            <p>To loſe ſuch an Opportunity as offered on <hi>Thurſday</hi> laſt, and now to trouble ſo good a King ſo oft, doubles your Petitioner's ſorrows.</p>
            <p>And that which adds to your Petitioner's miſery, is, that he cannot diſpoſe of his Witneſſes, till a poſitive Order be had; for which he humbly prays.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="note">
                        <head>Note theſe three following Preſidents.</head>
                        <p>I. THe Lord of <hi>Newport</hi> begg'd the <hi>Percies</hi> Land of the King, for the Duke of <hi>Monmouth,</hi> when the Duke was in <hi>France:</hi> but at the Duke's return, <hi>Percy</hi> the Claimant waited upon the Duke, to know his pleaſure; and told him, That my Solicitor had betrayed me, for the <hi>Percies</hi> Lands were begg'd without the Claimant's conſent or knowledge. Then the Duke replied, <hi>Mr.</hi> Percy, <hi>you ſhall have a fair Tryal at Law:</hi> And moreover he did promiſe he would not ſtand upon Priviledge: but when <hi>Percy</hi> was ready for a Tryal, then Trumpt up Priviledge. And Mr. <hi>Roſs</hi> the Duke's Agent ſaid, the Duke could not ſet aſide his Priviledge: But the Duke ſaid, if <hi>Percy</hi> proves himſelf Heir, I have no Right; and forth with ſold his Intereſt for an inconſiderable Sum of Money.</p>
                        <p>
                           <pb n="7" facs="tcp:47799:26"/>II. The Lord <hi>Ogle,</hi> that married the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Percy,</hi> would have aſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med the name of <hi>Percy;</hi> and put in a Bill to be made an Act to ſettle the Lands upon him by Act of Parliament.</p>
                        <p>III. And it is reported that the Lord of <hi>Eſſex</hi> deſired that ſome of thoſe Lands might be ſettled upon him by Act of Parliament.</p>
                        <p>By this account the Lands are yet unſettled: <hi>Ergo</hi> then great reaſon it is, that the true Heir-Male of the <hi>Percies</hi> Bill ſhould be made an Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, to ſettle the Name, Title and Eſtate together again, according to the firſt ſettlement confirmed by his Anceſtors.</p>
                        <p>Now your poor diſtreſſed and oppreſſed Petitioner humbly and freely offers, for the obtaining of Juſtice, and for the full ſatisfaction to the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty, and the Right Honourable Lords Spiritual and Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poral, and thoſe Honourable and Worthy Members of the Houſe of Commons in Parliament aſſembled, (if it be required and thought convenient, he being very unwilling to offer any thing that might give the leaſt offence, but rather ſubmit to their grave and mature Wiſdoms) theſe Propoſals following.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>James Percy</hi> the Claimant and Plaintiff, will pay into the hands of any Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtees that ſhall be appointed to receive the Money in Truſt for Mr. <hi>John Blake<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>'s Coſts, provided he likewiſe lay down the 90 <hi>l.</hi> taken by ſurprize out of Court before the Tryal was ended.</p>
                        <p>And Mr. <hi>
                              <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>tting</hi>'s Coſt likewiſe ſhall be paid, for what Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi> claims; provided likewiſe that Sir <hi>John Coppleston</hi> pay the 10 <hi>l.</hi> down, which he got when he ventured the Breach of Priviledge of Parliament: provided the whole Merits of the Cauſe may have a fair Hearing and Determination be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Lords: And if the Plaintiff and Claimant <hi>James Percy,</hi> doth not prove himſelf to be the right true and next Heir-Male in Bloud of the <hi>Percies</hi> of <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland,</hi> then let them take all the Money, and the Plaintiff will freely ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quit his Claim for ever, and remain till death a Loyal Subject, and <hi>James Percy.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Although his Witneſſes be diſpers'd, a Weeks time will bring them to Town again, upon the ſight of an Order.</p>
                        <p>For the Claimant <hi>James Percy</hi> (by Birth) ought to enjoy the Place, Seat and Priviledge of his Anceſtors, Earls of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> but now he dares not appear, till an Order be had.</p>
                        <p>Therefore he moſt humbly prays, That a fair Hearing may be had, and that a true deciſion of his juſt Cauſe and Claim may be made, according to Juſtice: ſo that the Innocent may be preſerved, and that the fraudulent practices not juſt may march off with ſhame: For Heroick Actions glorifies God, Honours the King, and makes all the people ſhout for joy.</p>
                        <p>God hath been pleaſed to make a true deciſion himſelf, which may be a preſident; for he ſent the Claimant from his Mothers Womb with a Creſcent into the World, which is Gods Enſign of Truth, and the very Badge belonging to the <hi>Percies</hi> Earls of <hi>Northumberland.</hi> In witneſs to this Truth, I have ſet to my Hand and Seal, this 3d. of <hi>January,</hi> 1680/1.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>JAMES PERCY. <figure>
                                 <figDesc>depiction of half-moon</figDesc>
                              </figure>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:47799:27"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the KINGS moſt Excellent Majeſty. <hi>The Humble Petition of</hi> JAMES PERCY.</head>
                        <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                        <p>THat it is a great grief to your Petitioner's Soul, to trouble your Sacred Majeſty ſo often, in looking after his Juſt Right; yet cannot help it. by reaſon his Opponents are of ſo great Power, Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licy and Force.</p>
                        <p>That notwithſtanding his Petition to the Right Honourable Houſe of Lords, preſented the day after his Hearing ſhould have been had, the Opponents got that Writ of Error diſmiſs'd the Houſe, well knowing the Errors would have been confirmed againſt them.</p>
                        <p>That thereby they have an opportunity to take out Execution againſt your Petitioner, and ſo to ſtop his further publick appearing.</p>
                        <p>That if that Writ be not recall'd into the Lords Houſe again, your Petitioner can in no wiſe expect a fair Hearing, nor a juſt de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciſion of his Cauſe.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>Therefore your oppreſſed Petitioner most humbly prays, That your Majeſty would be graciouſly pleaſed to ſee Justice done herein, and that a new Day may be appointed, according to the Prayer of that Petition that is now before the Houſe of Lords; or that your Sacred Majeſty will be graciouſly pleaſed to call your Loyal Subject, by your Royal Writ of Summons, to take the Place and Seat of his Ancestors, Earls of</hi> Northumberland, <hi>he having proved his legitimate Deſcent and Pedigree at ſeveral Tryals at Law.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                        <postscript>
                           <p>This Petition was preſented into his Sacred Majeſties hand <hi>Jan.</hi> 3. 1681.</p>
                           <p>All great and dubious matters the Children of <hi>Iſrael</hi> preſented and laid open before <hi>Moſes:</hi> Even ſo the Claimant hath done to his Majeſty all along, knowing that in the King ſolely lyes the creation and preſervation of Honour and Nobility.</p>
                           <p>But the King referred the Cauſe to the Lords to hear and determine; and now the two Writs of Error are diſmiſs'd the Lords Houſe, without hearing the ſaid Cauſe.</p>
                           <p>Now the Claimant <hi>James Percy</hi> finding himſelf over-powered, is forc'd to Appeal, and humbly prays for Juſtice: As Prerogative belongs to the King, ſo Property and Right belongs to his People.</p>
                        </postscript>
                        <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:27"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the KING'S Moſt Excellent Majeſty; <hi>The Humble Petition of</hi> JAMES PERCY.</head>
                        <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
                        <p>THat Your Petitioner moſt Humbly Beſeecheth, and Earneſtly Prayeth Your Majeſties Pardon, for that Omiſſion on the Ninth of <hi>December</hi> laſt, which was in truth altogether the Neglect of his <hi>Attorny,</hi> as his Printed Petition ſets forth.</p>
                        <p>That Your Petitioner Humbly preſents theſe two Books, that your Moſt Excellant Majeſty may ſee the real endeavours of Your Petitioner; and the firſt Book was Prepared for the Right Honourable Lords Spiritual and Temporal, to inform their Lordſhips: And the ſecond Book is prepared to make his Complaints known to the Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                              <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                           </gap> that They <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ay intercede in his Juſt Cauſe with Your Royal Majeſty, and the Right <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>onourable Lords in Parliament.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Therefore Your Majeſties Loyal Subject and Petitioner moſt Humbly Prays, That Your Royal Majeſty will be Graciouſly pleaſed, Patiently to Read, and Seriouſly conſider the Printed Complaints, and do Your Poor diſtreſſed Petitioner Juſtice, in reſtoring him by Your own Princely Power, Prerogative, and Clemency: He having at Law, fully proved his Pedigree: And therefore hath prepared a Bill, that it may be made an Act of Parliament, and moſt Humbly Prays Your Majeſties Royal Aſſent thereunto. And that Your Majeſties Royal Writ of Summons may forthwith call Your Loyal Subject, from the Houſe of Priſon, to the Houſe of Peers: And there to take the Place and Seat of his Anceſtors, Earls of <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland.</hi>
                           </hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>When King <hi>Pharao</hi> took <hi>Joſeph</hi> out of the <hi>Dungion,</hi> Then God fil'd <hi>Pharao's</hi> Barns with his Bleſſings. To which God Annex long Life, and a Proſperous Reign.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>And Your Petitioner ſhall Pray, JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>This Petition was preſented into his Sacred Majeſties Hand <hi>Jan.</hi> the 17th. 1681. And did indeavour to preſent the two Books mentioned in the Petition; But a Gentleman ſtepping betwixt the King and my ſelf, puſht me away; ſo that I could not Preſent the Complaint prepared for the Houſe of Lords, againſt the day of Hearing: Nor this Complaint which is prepared for the Houſe of Commons, (<hi>my Opponants are great and Numerous,</hi>) which forces the Claimant to Pray for Juſtice.</p>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:28"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="affidavit">
                        <head>An Affidavit made by <hi>JAMES PERCY,</hi> Claimant to the Earldom of <hi>NORTHUMBERLAND.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>WHereas Mr. <hi>James Hooton,</hi> did undertake the Carrying in two Writs of Error in Parliament, between <hi>James Percy</hi> Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff, and <hi>John Blackeſton,</hi> 
                           <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Defendant, for Scandalous Words, and in Ejectments for Lands, <hi>Robert <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>tting</hi> Gent. Leſſee of the Plaintiff, and Sir <hi>John Copleſton</hi> Defendant; And the aforeſaid Mr. <hi>Hooton</hi> did receive Writings of <hi>Percy</hi> the Claimant long before the day of Hearing before the Lords; And did promiſe to fix all the Claimants Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viats, ſo as they might be ready for ſome Lords, and for the Council: But when the Claimant ſhould have been prepared for his Counſel, then Mr. <hi>Hooton</hi> could not be found till the very Morning the Hearing ſhould have been had; then he meeting the Deponent <hi>James Percy,</hi> at <hi>Fetter-lane-end</hi> in <hi>Fleet-street,</hi> and ſaid whither are you going? <hi>Percy</hi> told him, <hi>I am a going to make my Complaint againſt You, for keeping my Writings, and not making my Breviats ready for my Council:</hi> And when <hi>James Percy</hi> had made his com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint in <hi>Parliament,</hi> and offered to make Oath before their Lordſhips to Confirm the truth: And when the Lords Commanded to withdra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                           <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> then Mr. <hi>James Hootons Man</hi> came into the <hi>Lobby,</hi> and there delivered the Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings to the Deponent, upon the 9th. of <hi>December</hi> 1678. Moreover the ſaid <hi>Hooton,</hi> ſaid ſome time before, that he was offered a Hundred <hi>Guin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys</hi> to betray the ſaid Deponents Caſe.</p>
                        <p>And on the 7th. of <hi>January</hi> 1681. The ſaid <hi>Hooton</hi> came to the Deponants Chamber, and deſired to ſee thoſe Writings that belonged to thoſe Writs of Errors, and did Write ſomething out of them; ſaying, <hi>He had not kept a Copy of them, which he ought to have done;</hi> but ſaid <hi>He had enough now to do his buſineſs:</hi> and further ſaid, <hi>there was one ſheet wanting:</hi> Which ſhews how careful he was of his Claimants Cauſe; And yet threatens he will Sue the Claimant for Defaming him in his Practiſe.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                           <dateline>
                              <hi>Jur'</hi> 18. <hi>die</hi> January 1680. <hi>coram me Magistro Canc'</hi> John Hoskyns.</dateline>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>The Deponant Humbly Prays for ſpeedy Juſtice, and that he may be forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with called from the Priſon of</hi> Kings-Bench, <hi>into Parliament, to take the Place of his Anceſtors, Earls of</hi> Northumberland, <hi>according to his Birth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right, and that the two Writs of Error, may be Re-manded back, and the Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution ſtopt. For his Witneſſes continue ſtill in Town: Hoping by your Mature Wiſdoms, to obtain an Order for a new day of Hearing; for which he Prays, as by his Petition all along appears.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:28"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="affidavit">
                        <head>An <hi>Affidavit</hi> made by <hi>JAMES PERCY</hi> Claimant to the Earldom of <hi>NORTHUMBERLAND.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>WHereas <hi>Adlard Welby</hi> Gent. is Attourny for <hi>John Blackſton</hi> 
                           <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                           <hi>Def.</hi> this Deponent <hi>James Percy</hi> on the 21<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>h. inſtant, went to <hi>Mr. Welby,</hi> and offer'd an Agreement: And whereas Coſt of 70 odd <hi>l.</hi> is demanded of me the Plaintif, the Deponent demanded 90 <hi>l.</hi> which was but tendred into Court upon my Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Scrogs</hi>'s promiſe that the Lord of <hi>Eſſex</hi> would not inſiſt upon Priviledge, and that the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent JAMES PERCY ſhould have a fair Tryal: the Money was not intended for the L. of <hi>Eſſex</hi> really, but it ought to have been reman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded back again to the Plaintiff JAMES PERCY; for that 90 <hi>l.</hi> coſts pretended for <hi>Mr. Clark,</hi> was Sued for by Capt. <hi>Biggerſtaff</hi> that mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried the Relict of <hi>Mr. Clark;</hi> And that 90 <hi>l.</hi> Coſts ought to have been ſet aſide upon their own Demurrer; therefore <hi>Mr. Welby</hi> Reply'd, I muſt complain in Court: The <hi>Writs of Error</hi> ought to have been heard, debated, and determined by the Right Honourable <hi>Lords</hi> in <hi>Parliament;</hi> But it was blown over, as by the Printed Complaint, (prepared to preſent to the Honourable Houſe of Commons appears) But it is hoped the Writs of Error may be Re-manded back into Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, to have a fair Hearing: Or if the Plaintiff and Deponent be forced to pay the 70 odd Pounds Coſt; then the 90 <hi>l.</hi> ought to be Refunded to the Deponent,</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                           <dateline>
                              <hi>Jurat.</hi> 
                              <date>22. die <hi>Jan.</hi> 1680.</date> John Hoskins.</dateline>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>IT is very hard for a man to be kept out of Poſſeſſion, and his Opponents mannage all their Suits at <hi>Law</hi> againſt him with his own Eſtate; and that will not ſerve their turns, but they covet to get from the Claimant by Fraud, ſo that they may totally Ruine and diſable him from proſecuting his Birth-right.</p>
            <p>JAMES PERCY, (the true and lawful Heir-male to the <hi>Percy's</hi> Earls of <hi>Northumberland,</hi>) hath found more <hi>Injuſtice</hi> and <hi>Hardſhips</hi> here in <hi>England,</hi> than the Children of <hi>Iſrael</hi> found in <hi>Egypt,</hi> when they made Brick, and were forc'd to gather their own Straw to burn them.</p>
            <p>When <hi>Joſeph's</hi> good Works were forgot, then his Brethren ſuffer'd; But now the PERCY'S good deeds are forgot, their lawful Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſor ſuffers in Priſon; And therefore earneſtly prays for a ſpeedy De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liverance. My great Pains, and Charge in Printing, is really inten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded rightly to inform the world, thereby to remove Oppreſſion, and to revive juſtice.</p>
            <q>
               <pb facs="tcp:47799:29"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="petition">
                        <head>To the Kings Moſt Excellent Majeſty. <hi>The Humble Petition of</hi> JAMES PERCY.</head>
                        <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
                        <p>THat Your Petitioners Opponents have obtain'd their Deſires, for your Petitioner is in Priſon</p>
                        <p>That Your Majeſty was Graciouſly pleaſed to ſay, <hi>God forbid that We ſhould hinder an Heir, but that he ſhould have the Benefit of the Law;</hi> And to that end Sir <hi>John Berkenhead</hi> was ſent by Your Majeſty to the Attourny General.</p>
                        <p>That Your Petitioner hath proved his Legitimacy and Pedegree, at four ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Tryals at Law, whereof one is exemplified under the Great Seal of Your Majeſties Court of <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> (where Your Petitioner is now a Priſoner) upon that Writ of Error the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Soroggs</hi> ſo wilfully gave the Cauſe away, after Your Petitioner had fully proved his Pedegree, and to be Deſcended from the Body of <hi>Henry Percy,</hi> fifth Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and Couſin and next Heir-Male to <hi>Joſceline Percy,</hi> late and eleventh Earl, deceaſed.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <hi>Therefore He moſt Humbly Prays that Your Moſt Excellent Majeſty would be Graciouſly pleaſed to Order the</hi> Lord Chancellour <hi>forthwith to call (by Your Majeſties Royal Writ of Summous) Your Petitioner from the</hi> Houſe of Priſon, <hi>to the</hi> Houſe of Peers, <hi>to take the Place and Seat of his Anceſtors Earls of</hi> Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland, <hi>as it is his Birth-right and Title proved at Law: God in his Justice and Mercy reſtor'd Your Majeſty to Your Crown and Kingdoms: even, ſo let Your Majeſty in Equity and Pity Reſtore Your poor Diſtreſſed Subject,</hi>
                           <signed>And Your Petitioner ſhall ever Pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                        </closer>
                        <postscript>
                           <p>THis Petition was offer'd to His Majeſty the 24th. of <hi>January</hi> 1680/1. and His Majeſty was pleas'd to ſay, <hi>He would not receive it;</hi> But ſaid, <hi>You may go where You pleaſe;</hi> Which Saying was taken for an Anſwer to that Petition pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented the 17 of <hi>January;</hi> Wherein it was to be underſtood, the Petitioner had prepared his Complaints for the Houſe of Commons. <hi>(It is to be noted,)</hi> That the Gentlemen who attended the King, ſaid, <hi>Yonder is the E. of</hi> Northumberland <hi>with a Petition; why ſhould Your Majeſty trouble Your ſelf with it? had You not one the other day? reject it.</hi> I have found His Moſt Excellent Majeſty hath been in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clinable to Juſtice all along, but ſtill is obſtructed by one means or other: But the plain Truth is, His Majeſty would not be ſeen to give and ungive at his own pleaſure, His Majeſty being miſtaken in his Guifts; Therefore was Graci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly pleaſed the Lords ſhould Hear and Determine the ſaid Cauſe; And to that purpoſe, did come down to the Bar in the Houſe of Lords to hear the Cauſe Himſelf; but was diſappointed, (as by the <hi>Petitions</hi> and <hi>Affidavits</hi> appear.) But the ſaid Cauſe having been continued a long time at ſuch a vaſt Charge; and then to be ſlightly blown over without a fair Hearing, all the World much admires; For the clearing up of the Pedigree, would have confirm'd the <hi>Errors.</hi>
                           </p>
                           <closer>Therefore Your Petitioner Appeals to the Honourable Houſe of Commons; And most Humbly and Earnestly prays your Aſſiſtance, to enquire the Reaſon why, and how the <hi>Writts of Errors</hi> came to be diſmiſt; And that they may be Re-manded back, that a fair Hear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing may be had according to the Prayer of the Petitions; Or that You will be pleaſed to cauſe the Heralds to enquire into the Truth of the Claimants Pedigree; And that He may be call'd from the <hi>Kings Bench</hi> Priſon, to the Houſe of Peers, to take the Place and Seat of his Anceſtors, Earls of <hi>Northumberland.</hi>
                              <signed>And Your Petitioner ſhall ever Pray, <hi>&amp;c. JAMES PERCY.</hi>
                              </signed>
                           </closer>
                        </postscript>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <pb facs="tcp:47799:29"/>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Right Honourable,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>I Am your Couſin, (though a Priſoner) deſcended from the Body of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> 5th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> By which Deſcent I am Couſin and next Heir-male to <hi>Joſceline Percy</hi> your Father the hite and 11th. Earl of <hi>Northumber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> Deceaſed. A Priſon is a Grave for Men alive; But when <hi>Naboth</hi> was ſton'd to death, then <hi>Ahab</hi> took poſſeſſion of the Vinyard, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 21.18. <hi>And walk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the Garden among the Beds of Pleaſure, then God ſent his Prophet</hi> Elias, <hi>to tell</hi> Ahab <hi>of his Tranſgreſſion,</hi> (notwithſtanding he was a King.) Ezekiel 46.18. <hi>When</hi> Belſhazzar <hi>wac quaffing in the Gold and Silver Veſſels of the Temple, then ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear'd the Hand-writing upon the Wall,</hi> Dan. 5. When your late Husband the Lord <hi>Ogle</hi> went about to aſſume the name of <hi>Percy,</hi> and to have the <hi>Percies</hi> Lands ſettled upon him by Act of <hi>Parliament,</hi> then God call'd him to Accompt; Therefore let Your Ladiſhip do Juſtice ſpeedily, and ſubmit to Truth in Time, for fear God calls You to Accompt alſo. I believe Your Servants and Agents have rendred Me to You to be a Monſter, and not a Man; Be not too ſubject to Believe Them, but ſee with your own Eys, and hear with your own Ears; and admit Me into Your preſence, for I have ſomthing to offer that will add Fame to Your Honour, and Rank You with thoſe Two Worthy Women of our Family, the Lady <hi>Agnes Percy,</hi> who preſerved the <hi>Percies</hi> Name, and the Lady <hi>Lucy,</hi> that ſettled her Eſtate upon the Heirs Males of the <hi>Percies</hi> for ever; And for ever that Eſtate muſt attend the Title; And the Fines can never be recover'd but by the true Heir-Male of the <hi>Percies</hi> Mr. <hi>Gee</hi> can inform You (if he pleaſes,) how I was at <hi>Petworth</hi> in the Year 1654. And then, and there made my Claim as I do now; And before Mr. <hi>Clark</hi>'s Tryal, Your Agents, with their Councel, would have own'd Me to be the next Heir, and would have aſſiſted Me for the Title with their Books, Pedigree and Records: And alſo how I met with Mr. <hi>Champian</hi> and Mr. <hi>Gee</hi> at Doctor <hi>Lampley's</hi> Houſe, and there made out my Pedigree clear, only I could not find out my Great Grand-fathers Name; Firſt, it was a very hard Name; And Secondly, Mr. <hi>Champian</hi> kept it ſecret till he was forc'd to declare upon his Oath, that Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy</hi> was Married, and had Sons and Daughters, at Sir <hi>John Coppleſton</hi>'s Tryal for <hi>Cannington</hi> and <hi>Rodaway</hi> Lands in <hi>Somerſetſhire.</hi> Thirdly, The <hi>Heralds</hi> had altogether neglected the Collateral Line of the <hi>Percies.</hi> Now all my Aim is really to beget a right underſtanding, ſo that I may remain,</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your Ladiſhips Real, Cordial, and Faithful Kinſman, and moſt Humble Servant, <hi>JAMES PERCY.</hi>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>
               <hi>What I have to declare to your Ladyſhip is not convenient to be committed to writing, but aſsure your ſelf it really tends to your preſent Welfare, and future Peace and Proſperity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An Anſwer will find me in the <hi>Kings-Bench-Rules,</hi> at the Written Table at Captain <hi>Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer</hi>'s Houſe in <hi>Lombard-ſtreet,</hi> near the <hi>Bowling-green,</hi> in the Borough of <hi>Southwark.</hi>
            </p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <head>This Letter was preſented the day of the date hereof; and the Claymant hath printed it, that the world may ſee that a true <hi>Percy</hi> is not aſhamed of his Innocent and Juſt Cauſe, nor affraid of his Potent Opponents; <hi>For he whom I truſt in, is greater than they,</hi> 5 Eccleſ. ver. 8.</head>
                  <p>☞ NOw in theſe our days there is no Prophet <hi>God, Michaia, Elijah,</hi> nor Interpreters of Dreams, like <hi>Joſeph</hi> and <hi>Daniel,</hi> that dares preſume to ſpeak to Kings as they did in thoſe days.</p>
                  <p>Therefore <hi>James Percy,</hi> the true Heir male of the <hi>Percies,</hi> Earls of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> humbly makes bold with the Prophet <hi>Ezekiel,</hi> cap. 46. ver. 18. <hi>Moreover the Prince ſhall not take of the Peoples Inheritance by oppreſſion, but he ſhall give his Sons Inheritance out of his own Poſſeſſion, that my People be not ſcattered every man from his Poſſeſſion.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <pb facs="tcp:47799:30"/>The King's Moſt Excellent Majeſtie's Gracious Anſwer was to the Claimant's firſt Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, in 1670. <hi>God forbid that we ſhould hinder an Heir, but that he ſhould have the Benefit of the Law:</hi> And to that purpoſe His Maj<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſty ordered Sir <hi>John Berkenhead</hi> (Maſter of Reequeſts then in w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>iting<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> to go to the Attorney General, to know why he refuſed to ſign the Co-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant which the Claymants Sollicitor, Mr. <hi>Thomas Swain</hi> preſented to him to ſign? But the Attorney General ſaid, <hi>He could n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>t ſign</hi> Percie<hi>'s Co-warrant, by reaſon that he was of Council for the Counteſs of</hi> Northumberland: And the Court of Wards being put down did much <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dernize the Claimant in his Proceedings, and to leſs than nine ſeveral Perſons have ſtood up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and been ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ter'd under Priviledge, which hath been the cauſe of delay all this time.</p>
                  <p>And from that time Mr. <hi>Swayn</hi> (the Claymant's Sollicitor) began to play the Devil with two ſticks; for whilſt <hi>James Percy</hi> was proſecuting the Law, and delivering Declarations in Ejectments in the North, the Sollicitor had contriv'd the buſineſs ſo, as the Title and Lands were begg'd, diſpos'd and ſcatter'd before the Claymant returned, and then pretended the Co-warrant, with other Writings, was loſt, which coſt a conſiderable Sum of Money, and then arreſted his Clyent <hi>James Percy</hi> in three ſeveral Suits at Law, which continued three years; But the Sollicitor <hi>Swayn</hi> was overthrown in all the 3 Actions; moreover the Claymant <hi>James Percy</hi> was <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> thoſe travels poiſoned at <hi>New-Caſtle,</hi> arreſted at <hi>York</hi> in two Actions of 20000 <hi>l.</hi> each Action<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and then durſt not proceed at Law, but let the Actions fall, and paid 40 <hi>s.</hi> Coſt, a poor ſatisfaction for a night and two days Impriſonment, and maintaining my two Men and three Horſes, beſides the Charge of ſpunging Bums; And the Actions were in the Lord of <hi>Eſſex,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Clark,</hi> and others Names: And to fill up the meaſure of malice, they publiſhed in the <hi>Engliſh Gazette,</hi> and the <hi>French Gazette, That the Claymant was an Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſtor;</hi> And Mr. <hi>Blackſton</hi> ſaid in all theſe Courts, <hi>That the Claymant's Name was not</hi> Percy, but declared him to be a Baſtard; with many more ſcandalous wordr, which were proved at that Tryal before the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Scroggs,</hi> notwithſtanding he diſcharged Mr. <hi>Bla<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>k<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi> and Sir <hi>George Jeffreys</hi> at that Tryal, took Fees on both ſides, ſo the Claymant <hi>James Percy</hi> was clearly bought and ſold, and proved to his Damage 12000 <hi>l.</hi> Beſides, it was the occaſion of this his preſent Impriſonment, upon the Writs of Error that were ſo ſtrangely diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſs'd the Houſe of Lords without any Hearing; notwithſtanding the renewing and conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuing after every Prorogation, coſt in all above 300 <hi>l.</hi> And now the Claymant <hi>James Percy</hi> hath uſed all ways and means poſſible, (as by his Petition and publick Prints appears) and cannot proceed further without the Aſſiſtance of the Honourable Houſe of Commons. His Majeſty is much troubled, and the Claymant really believes that His Majeſty had a cordial Deſire to hear and ſee the Cauſe determined, as by His coming up to the Bar of the Houſe of Lords, that day the Hearing ſhould have been had. Beſides, His Majeſty may perceive, I ſhall never leave my Claim, till Juſtice be done, by reaſon I now know it is my Right by Birth and Bloud, and that the ſole power of creating and preſerving Honour reſts in His Royal Breaſt, as Flowers in the Crown: And by the Coronation Oath, the King cannot take Titles from one Peer, to give to another Peer. But as God hath in mercy reſtored His Majeſty to His Crown and Kingdoms, even ſo ought the King in Juſtice to reſtore every Loyal Subject to the Birth-right, Title and Inheritance of his Anceſtors. It was very hard at firſt for the Claymant to find out the Name of his great Grandfather, by reaſon he was in his Childhood brought up amongſt his Mothers Relations; And in the troubleſome times (he being a Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alliſt) was forced to abſcond and travel for many years, <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                        <desc> _____ </desc>
                     </gap> But the Adverſaries did wildernize the Claymant, in hiding his great Grandfathers Chriſtian Name from him: For Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy</hi> was the Claymant <hi>James Percie</hi>'s Great Grandfather, and youngeſt Son of <hi>Henry Percy</hi> 5th. Earl of <hi>Northumberland;</hi> and this Collateral Line was never attain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted; and therefore ought to be reſtored according to <hi>Henry Percy</hi> the 5th. Earls Patent, and not under the Patent of the New-Creation by Queen <hi>Mary</hi> for <hi>Thomas Percy,</hi> 2d. Son of the 5th. Earl, was attainted, but Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy</hi> 3d. Son was Innocent, and ſo hath his Iſſue con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued to this day: And therefore prays for ſpeedy Juſtice: Juſtice removes oppreſſion, Glori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fies God, Honours the King, Rejoyces the People, puts an end to your troubles, and ratifies Peace, for which the Petitioner prays.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>For <hi>Henry Percy, 5th.</hi> Earl, Great Great Grandfather, had Sir <hi>Ingelram Percy,</hi> Great Grandfather, who had <hi>Henry Percy</hi> Grandfather, and he had <hi>Henry Percy</hi> Father of the Claymant. JAMES PERCY.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
